洛杉磯，加利福利亞州
1977年
你喜歡我的車嗎？
How do you like my car,
大男孩
Big Boy?
泳池邊的一堂課
巴特、莎拉和喬納森
NARRATOR: Bart, Sarah and Jonathan
今天一起去公共泳池玩耍
are spending their leisure day at the city pool.
他們是不是很幸運呢？
Aren't they lucky?
讓我們瞧瞧他們今天帶了什麼去泳池
Let's see what they have brought with them to the pool today.
巴特帶的毛巾是淺色的
Bart has a plain towel.
莎拉帶的毛巾是深色的
Sarah has a bright towel.
喬納森帶的毛巾是彩色的
Jonathan has a gay towel.
現在的孩子都有個毛病
JACKSON: There's something wrong with kids today.
他們太早熟
They know too much.
就拿這個小美人來說
Take this little gem.
她才13歲
She's 13.
就已經榜上了個公子哥
Already she's got herself a winner.
儘管他的年齡是她的3倍
Sure, he's three times her age,
可他有錢買大麻啊
but he's got money for pot
而且還開的是好車
and he drives a nice car.
誰最能幹？寶貝，誰最能幹？
Who's the man, baby? Who's the man?
- 你啊，你最能幹了  - 恩，說得對
- You are. You're the man.  - Yeah. That's right.
- 我就是這麼能幹  - 歐也，你是我的性感男神
- That's right. I'm the man.  - Oh, yes. You're my foxy-fox.
我不否認自己過去也是個小痞子
JACKSON: I'm not saying I wasn't a little bastard.
因為我是愛爾蘭裔
I mean, I grew up Irish.
又是在布朗克斯的河谷區長大（紐約貧民區，犯罪率高）
The Bronx. Riverdale.
我幹的不是正當職業，黃頁裡也查不到我的信息
I don't have a job title, I'm not in the Yellow Pages,
可要是有人找你的麻煩
but if you got trouble with someone,
有人勾搭你的未成年閨女
someone's messing around with your underage daughter,
你可以四處打聽下我，傑克遜·希利
you might ask around for me, Jackson Healy.
- 你就是那傢伙？  - 什麼？
- Are you the man?  - What?
別再去勾搭小姑娘
Stay away from little girls.
愛情，多偉大啊，對吧？我曾經愛過一次
Love. Grand, isn't it? I was in love once.
婚姻就是給你恨的人買棟房子
Marriage is buying a house for someone you hate.
記住了
Remember that.
我身旁是底特律的汽車廠商代表
I'm here with a representative of the Detroit Auto Manufacturers,
貝根·保爾森閣下
Mr Bergen Paulsen.
保爾森閣下，很高興能請到你
And, Mr Paulsen, glad to have you here.
我明白你是專程來參加汽車展的
I understand that you're in town for the big show.
跟我們介紹一下吧
Tell us a little bit about it.
瞧瞧我們推出的這一批耀眼的車子
Take a look at this outstanding line-up we have here for you.
它們性能非凡，說是能自動駕駛也不為過
These cars are so incredible, they practically drive themselves.
我必須得問你
REPORTER: I do have to ask you
“三巨頭”最近被起訴的事
about the allegations about collusion
三巨頭：通用汽車、福特和克萊斯勒，總部均在底特律
“三巨頭”最近被起訴的事
about the allegations about collusion
三巨頭：通用汽車、福特和克萊斯勒，總部均在底特律
他們被指
- in regards to...
三巨頭：通用汽車、福特和克萊斯勒，總部均在底特律
串通一氣
...a smog control device,
三巨頭：通用汽車、福特和克萊斯勒，總部均在底特律
掩蓋一個煙霧控制部件上的作假行為
the recent lawsuit against the Big Three.
三巨頭：通用汽車、福特和克萊斯勒，總部均在底特律
掩蓋一個煙霧控制部件上的作假行為
the recent lawsuit against the Big Three.
我不會回應無端的指責
BERGEN: I'm not gonna dignify that...
這裡是馬奇偵探所
HOLLAND: You have reached March Investigations.
接下來是電話錄音
This machine records messages.
聽到滴一聲後請講話
Wait for the tone and speak clearly.
是你閨女在說話
HOLLY: This is your daughter speaking.
今天是星期四，你沒忘記吧？ 是我的生日哦
Thursday, as you may remember, is my birthday.
給我買禮物哦
Please give accordingly.
另外還要提醒你別忘記了
Also I hope you didn't forget that
今天你有正事要辦
you're supposed to be working today.
你永遠都不會快樂
我希望天上能掉餡餅
HOLLAND: I wish I wished for things, man.
我家人對我說去爭取實現遠大理想
My folks, they told me to reach for the stars,
而我警隊的同事對我說去爭取加官進爵
and then my pals in the force said reach for the brass ring,
在我妻子去世後
and then my wife died
只要能讓我付得起1塊5一加侖的油錢，什麼活我都會爭取
and I reached for whatever came in a gallon and cost a buck fifty.
我妻子常說我沒有長遠打算
She used to say I got no follow-through.
我車開到半路碾上釘子，就動不了了
I hit nails in halfway and stop.
巴西“殺人蜂”繼續肆虐
我車開到半路碾上釘子，就動不了了
I hit nails in halfway and stop.
巴西“殺人蜂”繼續肆虐
她說得一點沒錯
- She's not wrong.
嘿，排隊啊，混球
MAN: Hey, there's a line, asshole!
嘿，你想幹嘛啊？
Hey, what are you doing?
幾年前這裡開始實施無過錯離婚制度
They implemented a no-fault divorce here a couple of years back
這真的害慘了一批人
that really screwed things up.
很多私家偵探都因此失業
A lot of private cops folded.
我倖免於難，因為本地退休社區裡的一個傢伙
Not me. I got this guy in a local retirement park.
他總有案子給我
He kicks a few cases my way.
是我丈夫
WOMAN: It's my husband.
他叫佛瑞德
Fred's his name.
佛瑞德
Fred.
- 他失蹤了  - 失蹤？
- He's gone missing.  -Missing?
我擔心得要死
WOMAN: I'm terribly worried.
因為佛瑞德從來沒有走過這麼久
It's just Fred's never been gone this long before.
他失蹤多久了？
How long has he been missing?
葬禮之後就不見了
Since the funeral.
那好，我馬上就著手調查
Well, I can start right away.
- 你是艾蜜莉雅？  - 希利先生？
- Amelia?  - Mr Healy.
我認為有2個人
Um, I think there's two of them,
但我只有其中一人的名字和住址
but I only have the name and description for the one.
- 你能把他們打發走嗎？  - 小菜一碟
- You can take care of them?  - Consider it done.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 你這麼說我就放心了  - 我專門幹這個的
- I feel better already.  - It's my job.
他們一直跟蹤我，向我的朋友打聽我的下落
They've been following me around and asking my friends where I live.
我真的是嚇壞了
I've just been really scared,
你也許能給我些安全感
but, um, you make me feel safe.
你少給了
You're short.
我咋了？
I'm what?
你少給了7塊錢
You're $7 short.
好的
Right, um...
很抱歉
Sorry. Um...
有時候我感覺良好
JACKSON: Sometimes I feel okay about things.
很少有
Not often.
或許該搞個偵探執照
Could try for an investigator's licence.
做名私家偵探
Become a P.I.
那些傢伙能幫助別人
Those guys help people.
這樣的話，我早上起來心情也許會好些
Maybe then I'd feel good in the morning.
她是黑髮
She's got dark hair,
大約有這麼高吧
about yea high.
名字是艾蜜莉雅
Name's Amelia.
可能就住這附近
She might be from the neighbourhood.
- 沒見過，夥計，抱歉幫不了你  - 沒見過？
- No, can't help you, buddy.  - No?
抱歉
Sorry.
我的工作污穢不堪，捉姦，再捉姦
HOLLAND: I work in a cesspool. Sex. More sex.
我妻子經常說道，我就靠別人苟合來謀生
My wife, she used to say I make a living off rumpy-pumpy.
什麼溝河，她是英國人
Whatever. She was English.
我根本就不知道她說的是什麼意思
I don't know what the fuck it means either.
重點是，我可不在乎黃上校
The point is I don't care if Colonel Mustard
黃上校：妙探尋凶（圖版遊戲）裡的黃色棋子
是在書房裡用燭臺做的
did it in the study with a candlestick,
只要我能知道對方是誰和拍下照片
I just wanna know who he did it with and get the pictures.
恩，我想我記得
BARTENDER: Yeah, I think I remember her.
叫艾蜜莉雅對吧？
Amelia, right?
她3、4天前的晚上在這
Was in here three or four nights ago.
要了威士卡、馬丁尼之類的
Drank bourbon martinis.
那也太猛了吧
Well, that's disgusting.
她有沒有可能用信用卡付的款？
Any chance she, uh, paid with a credit card?
我像是給你打工的嗎？
As in, am I gonna pull the receipts for you?
沒那種可能吧
Fat fucking chance.
那是件T恤？
Is that a shirt?
- 是的  - 挺好看的
- Yeah.  - It's very pretty.
我自己做的
I made it myself.
是嗎？
Yeah?
我做了這個
I made this.
我可沒說過這很容易
HOLLAND: Look, I'm not saying it's easy.
我也沒說過你不需要速戰速決
I'm not saying you don't gotta think on your feet,
也許還要無視些法規
bend a few rules maybe,
可這一切都是值得的
but it's worth it,
只要你能拿到結果
as long as you get the results.
那... 那流了好多的血
Okay, that's it. That's a lot of blood.
那流了好多... 流好多的血
That is a lot... That's a lot of blood.
他要不行了，開快點
We're losing him. Go! Hurry up!
堅持住啊，別...
Now, don't go anywhere. Don't...
看著我，聽我說，先生
Stay with me. Stay with me! Sir.
現在告訴我，你願意找尋真主嗎
Now, tell me, are you willing to find God?
我想找到艾蜜莉雅
Look, I'm trying to find Amelia.
早上好，洛杉磯市民
NEWSCASTER: Good morning, Los Angeles.
今天再次發佈二級煙霧警報
Today, yet another stage-two smog alert.
空氣品質管理局提醒廣大市民，下午6點前避免外出
The A.Q.M.D. has cautioned residents not to stay outside
也別進行不必要的鍛煉活動
or engage in unnecessary exercise before 6:00 p.m.
另一則消息，警方發言人說他們並不排除
In other news, a police spokesman says he has not ruled out foul play
成人影星米絲蒂·芒滕絲是死於謀殺的可能
in the death of adult film star Misty Mountains,
上週二臨晨
whose car went off-road
她開車沖出馬路後身亡
in the early hours of last Tuesday.
現在回到最受美國人喜愛的家庭，《沃爾頓一家》
And now back to America's favourite family, The Waltons.
平心靜氣
"Equanimity.
一種冷靜、心平氣和的狀態
"The quality of being calm and even-tempered."
平心靜氣
He accepted her betrayal
你才能原諒她的背叛
with equanimity.
傑克，我跟你爸搞上了
Jack, I'm fucking your dad.
你說什麼？
What?
約翰·博伊...
John Boy...
六，七，八
Six, seven, eight...
一
One...
操
Fuck.
- 誰啊？  - 送信的
- HOLLAND: Who is it?  - Messenger service.
是霍蘭德·馬奇家嗎？
Holland March home?
搞什麼飛機？
What the fuck?
馬奇先生，我們下面玩個遊戲
Mr March, we're gonna play a game.
我覺得你走錯門了吧
I think you have the wrong house.
這個遊戲叫做“閉嘴聽指令”
It's called, "Shut up unless you're me."
我可喜歡這遊戲了
I love that game.
你是名私家偵探？
You're a private investigator?
錢包裡有二十塊，你全拿去吧
Look, there's 20 bucks in there, all right? Just take it.
我可不是為錢來的，我都說過是來送信的
No, I'm not here for that. I told you, I'm a messenger.
當私家偵探能住上這麼好的房子？
You can afford to live like this as a P.I.?
- 送的什麼信？  - 喔，對，對
- What's the message?  - Oh, right, right.
別再去找艾蜜莉雅了，明白？
Stop looking for Amelia, all right?
我不是要找她麻煩
I'm not even looking for Amelia.
她跟我的案子有關
She's a person of interest, man.
好吧，我不幹了，我保證不插手此事
Fine. I'm done. Put a fork in me.
我怕被你插死
Don't really put a fork in me.
聽你這麼說，艾蜜莉雅肯定會很高興的
Amelia's gonna be very happy that you got the message so quickly.
會讓她露出笑臉的，很好
It's gonna make her smile. That's good.
下面我還要問你件事
Now, I got one more thing I need
問完我就收工了
to ask you before we're done here.
- 你想知道誰雇的我  - 答對了，恩
- You wanna know who hired me.  - Bingo. Yeah.
我們可以好好商量，不然有你好看的
Now, we can do this the easy way or we can do it the hard way.
- 葛籣  - 什麼？
- Glenn.  - What?
莉莉·葛籣
Lily Glenn. Two N's.
週二時，老太太雇我去找她的侄女
Old lady hired me to find her niece on Tuesday.
你剛出賣了自己的客戶
You just gave up your client.
我可以選擇公開什麼資訊
I made a discretionary revelation.
不對，你出賣了她
No. No, you just gave her up.
就問你一個問題
I asked you one simple question.
你呱呱呱的，把什麼都告訴我了
You gave me all the information.
我以為你就想知道那些啊
I thought that's what you wanted.
什麼？
What?
你現在還沒聽懂我的話，真是很遺憾啊
Now, I'm very sorry that you didn't get the message.
就是，可我現在懂了
Me, too. But I get it now.
我懂了，我接受
I get it. I dig it.
媽的
Shit!
那現在呢？你現在懂我的意思了嗎？
What about now? You get the message now?
- 是的  - 你確定？
- Yep.  - Are you sure?
是的，我確定
Yeah, I'm cool.
那好，把你的左臂給我
All right. Give me your left arm.
什麼？
Huh?
你的左臂，把你的左臂給我
Your left arm. Give me your left arm. This one.
- 不行  - 快點給我
- No!  - Yeah, come on.
不給
No!
就不給
Get... No!
- 你割到自己了?  - 我正在養傷當中
- Did you cut yourself?  - I'm dealing with an injury.
好，你要是去見你醫生的話，
Right, look, when you're talking to your doctor,
告訴他
just tell him you have
你的左橈骨扭傷骨折了
a spiral fracture of the left radius.
不，不要
No! No.
- 深呼吸  - 別這樣
- Deep breath.  - No!
你不介意我吃個蘋果吧？
Do you mind if I have an apple?
好了，馬奇先生，希望你今天過得開心，好嗎
All right, Mr March. You have a good day, okay?
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey.
- 想來瓶呦呼嗎  - 呦呼？真的？
- Want a Yoo-hoo?  - A Yoo-hoo? Are you kidding?
歐也
Oh, yeah.
坦白說，我有30年沒喝過這玩意了
You know, I haven't had one of these in about 30 years.
你是我爸的朋友嗎？
Are you a friend of my dad's?
恩，我們是生意夥伴
Yeah, yeah. We're business associates.
他正在裡面休息呢
He's inside resting.
你剛才是不是在幾個街區外的一片空地上？
Didn't I see you crawling round a vacant lot a couple of blocks over?
可能吧，我有時會在那讀書
Um, maybe. I read there sometimes.
好的
Right.
謝謝你請我喝呦呼
"It's me-he for Yoo-hoo!" Thanks again.
再見
Bye.
一加侖汽油的價格又漲了1毛6
STAND-UP COMIC: Because the gas prices are up 16 cents a gallon,
美國現在<.i>
uh, the US now
正在尋找能作為替代品的燃料
is looking into alternative fuels.
有種方法，你添加玉米進去
There's a process where you can
就能產出汽油來
put corn in and gas comes out.
我雖不是什麼科學家
I'm no scientist,
可我一直就那麼幹的啊（指吃玉米放屁）
but that's been my process with corn for years.
嘿
MAN: Hey.
這上面不是公共場所
JACKSON: It's not a public area up here.
哇
MAN: Wow.
這就是你住的房子？
You got like an apartment up here?
你要找洗手間的話
If you're looking for the restroom,
是在樓下
back down the stairs.
我們是來找艾蜜莉雅的
We're looking for Amelia.
我真的看見她了，馬奇先生
MRS GLENN: I'm telling you, I saw her, Mr March.
這不是我的想像，我看見米絲蒂好生生的
I didn't imagine it. I saw my Misty alive.
葛籣夫人，理性點好嗎，這是件備受關注的案子
Mrs Glenn, be reasonable. This is a high-profile case.
你侄女是著名的...
Your niece is a very famous...
女演員
Actress,
而且是首席法醫親自做的鑒定
and the head medical examiner ID'd her himself.
我從前面窗戶看見她的
I saw her through the front window.
你看錯了
You didn't.
一清二楚，她穿著...
Clear as day. She was wearing...
細條紋外套，我知道，非常顯眼
The pinstriped suit. I know. Very specific.
她在寫些什麼
She was writing something and then
隨後出門開車走了
she came out and she drove away
這是車禍2天后的事
and this was two days after the accident.
我記得你說你找到她了
And I thought that you said you found her.
那額外報酬是幹嘛的？
Now, what was that bonus payment?
我從沒說過找到她了
I never said I found her.
我原話是我去追查了你看到的姑娘
I said I was tracking the girl that you saw
然後很可能是一個叫艾蜜莉雅的年輕姑娘
and that was probably this young lady, Amelia.
- 你為什麼不相信我？  - 葛籣夫人，米絲蒂死了
- Why don't you believe me?  - Mrs Glenn, Misty's dead.
她死於車禍
She died in that accident.
我一開始就不該收下你的錢
I never should have taken your money in the first place.
我向你鄭重道歉
I'm very sorry about that.
就算不是她，就算這個艾蜜莉雅不是我侄女
Even... No, even if this Amelia girl isn't my niece,
她可能知道點什麼
she might know something.
求求你了，你能繼續查下去嗎？
Please, please, will you keep looking?
不行
No.
馬奇先生
Mr March...
我能問你個問題嗎？老實回答我
Can I ask you a question? Tell me the truth.
別因為我是你爸就有所保留
And don't take it easy on me just 'cause I'm your father.
直言不諱的告訴我
You just tell it to me straight.
- 我是個混蛋嗎  - 是的
- Am I a bad person?  - Yes.
開你的車吧
Just drive.
我再問你一遍
MAN: I'm gonna ask you again.
艾蜜莉雅在哪？
Where is Amelia?
我也想幫你一把
I would like to help you,
可我認識的人裡沒有一個叫艾蜜莉雅的
but I just don't know anybody called Amelia.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
你再不開口，我就要擰斷
You don't talk, I'm gonna have to start
你的手指了
breaking your fingers.
聽明白了嗎?
You understand?
是的，我明白
Yes, I understand.
嘿，審問專家，過來一下
Hey, hotshot, come on in here.
我發現櫃子裡藏的有東西
I found something hidden in the cabinet.
真的？
Really?
看好他
Watch him.
別啊
Oh, no.
別打開那個，那不是我的東西
Hey, don't open that because that's not mine.
是一個朋友的
It belongs to a friend.
我只是幫他保管一下
I just, uh... I look after it for him.
不過那包有機關的
But it's one of those bags.
你要是強行打開的話
If you try to open it...
- 我操  - 糟糕
MAN: Oh, fuck! Fuck!  JACKSON: Shit!
操他媽的
Motherfucker!
- 我什麼都看不見  - 呵
- I can't see nothing.  - Yeah.
天哪，什麼玩意
Oh, God. What the fuck?
你知道那顏色是洗不掉的，對吧？
You know that colour doesn't come off, right?
我想提醒你的
I tried to tell you.
你想提醒我?
You tried to tell me?
- 操你媽  - 嘿，嘿，別這樣啊
- Fuck you!  - Hey, hey. Oh, no! Hey!
別拿我的魚撒氣啊
Not the fish. Come on.
嘿，你能讓這傢伙有點職業素養嗎？
Hey, can you ask this guy to behave like a professional?
小子，我要是奪過你的槍
You know, kid, when I get that gun off you,
那就是你的晚飯了
it's gonna be your dinner.
晚飯？
Dinner?
你還挺幽默的
It's fucking... You're funny. You're funny.
別，別這樣
Don't... Don't...
過來啊，魚兒
Come on, fish.
你想吃嗎？你想拿它做晚飯嗎？
You want some fucking dinner? Do you want some dinner?
你為什麼要這樣做？這樣只能幫倒忙
Why are you doing this? This is not gonna help you.
- 拿去吧  - 別這樣
- There you go.  - Now, come on.
你給我把它吃了，你個賤人
You're gonna eat that thing, you fucking fuck!
聽我說，你別被怒火沖昏了頭
Look, you gotta stop and think about this,
好嗎？
all right?
你今晚來我這裡
When you came here tonight,
就指望演這麼一出？
was this what you wanted to happen?
你過來是喂我吃魚的？
What, you came here to make me eat fish?
還是要給我來幾槍？
To shoot me?
你來我這裡
Look, if you come in here,
暴打我一頓，把屋裡砸得稀巴爛
you beat up on me, you trash the place,
我都理解，我明白
I understand, I get it,
這是你工作需要，我能接受，好嗎？
it's part of the job. I accept it, all right?
可你剛做了些什麼？
But what did you do?
你做了些完全沒道理的事，是不是呢?
You did something different from that, didn't you? Right?
你激怒我了，逼我與你為敵
You pissed me off. You made an enemy.
現在就算我真知道些什麼，我也不可能會告訴你了
Now, even if I knew something, I wouldn't tell you, kid.
你知道我為什麼不告訴你嗎？
And you know why I wouldn't tell you?
這並不是我唯一的原因
And this is... It's not my only reason,
但是是主要原因
but it is a principle reason.
我不告訴你是因為你太弱智了
You know, I wouldn't tell you'cause you're a fucking moron.
搞什麼...
What the...
你他媽的蠢貨
You stupid son of a bitch.
- 6碼，我穿6碼的  - 我穿7碼的
GIRL 1: Six. I'm a six. GIRL 2: I'm a seven!
- 六碼  - 7碼
- Six.  - Seven!
我的老天啊，一個一個的來
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Jesus Christ! One at a time!
你這樣說話是對主的不敬
You took the Lord's name in vain.
沒，哪有啊，珍妮特
No, I didn't, Janet.
我認為這樣是非常有幫助的，好嗎，珍妮特
I found it very useful, actually. Okay, Janet?
生日快樂
GIRL 3: Birthday girl!
馬奇，是我傑克遜·希利
March. Jack Healy.
別心慌，我不是來揍你的
Don't get upset. I'm not here to hurt you.
只是來問你件事
I just wanna ask you a question.
- 嘿，別開槍  - 你以為我有多白癡啊？
- Hey, no.  - How stupid do you think I am?
我可有持槍執照，傻逼
I got a licence to carry, motherfucker.
自從你那天來“拜訪”我後
Ever since your little visit the other day,
這個小寶貝就隨身攜帶了
this little baby's gonna stay right here.
操，我操
Fuck, fuck.
看那邊去
Look away.
從這面鏡子裡也看得到的，你知道吧？
You know there's a mirror here, right?
閉上你的雙眼
Close your eyes.
媽的，算了，你可以轉過來了
Fucking damn it. Forget it. You know what? Turn around.
- 我可以睜開眼了嗎  - 恩，睜開吧
- Can I open my eyes?  - Yeah, open your eyes.
你想幹嘛？
What do you want?
我想你去找艾蜜莉雅
I want you to find Amelia.
那你認為這些傢伙想傷害艾蜜莉雅？
So you think these guys are gonna hurt Amelia?
是的，可能想幹掉她
Sure, after they're done killing her.
我其實四處打聽了下你
You know, I asked around about you.
幾個我信的過的朋友都說你是個行家
There's a couple of people I trust say you're pretty good at this.
那可真是出乎意料啊，我還以為
Well, that's surprising. I would have thought
你擰斷我的手臂後，就收工了啊
your job ended with breaking my fucking arm.
沒錯，的確收工了
Well, you know, technically it did.
我現在是無償加班
I'm off the clock.
這是兩碼事
This is a separate situation.
你裝好人就想騙到我嗎，夥計
I'm not buying this nice guy act, pal.
她欠你錢吧，是不是？
She owes you money, doesn't she?
你想把錢要回來？
You're coming to collect?
你想讓我監視她
You want me to finger her
這樣你就有機會毀她的容，誰知道呢
so you can throw acid in her face? Well, no.
不是，她其實提前就付我錢了
No, she paid me up front, actually, you know.
我這麼做是因為我喜歡現在住的地方
What it is, for me, is I like where I live
而且也不打算搬家
and I don't wanna move.
那麼，提前付你兩天的報酬
So, two days in advance.
400塊
$400.
另外那老太太還會給你不少吧
Plus whatever the old lady's giving you.
老太太？去你的老太太
Old lady? Fuck you, old lady.
你擰斷了我的手臂，我退出了，記得嗎？
You broke my arm. I quit, remember?
那就給她打個電話，再接過案子就是了
So call her up, get back on the case.
能拿兩次錢呢
Get paid twice.
你給的這個理由挺充分啊
Wow, that is very telling.
可我們做私家偵探的，得按規矩辦事
I'm a detective, and we have a code.
我們不能那樣做
We don't do that.
不過多謝提醒，你的心意我領了
But interesting. Good to know.
- 好吧  - 心意我領了
- Okay.  - Good to know.
你一直在找艾蜜莉雅，對吧？
You were looking for Amelia, right?
是也不是
Yes and no.
什麼意思？
Excuse me?
我的職業很麻煩的，懂嗎？
My profession is very complicated, okay?
界限模糊
It's nuanced.
那是什麼意思？
What does that mean?
操
Fuck it.
上周這位老太太來找我
Last week, this old broad comes to me
雇我去找她的侄女
and she asks me to find her niece,
- 米絲蒂·芒滕絲  - 米絲蒂·芒滕絲？？
- Misty Mountains.  - Misty Mountains?
那個豔星，剛死的那個？
The porno actress? The one that died?
也是個年輕姑娘，年輕的豔星
The young lady. The porno young lady.
恩沒錯，她出車禍死了
But, yeah, she died in a crash
可是2天過後
and then two days later
老太太去她的住處清理屋子
her aunt goes to her house to clean out the place,
然後奇跡出現了
and lo and behold,
米絲蒂·芒滕絲，好生生的在那
alive and well, Misty Mountains.
老太太隔著窗戶看見她的
She sees her through the window.
她看見米絲蒂上了車
She sees her get in her car.
- 她看見米絲蒂開走了  - 胡扯吧
- She sees her drive away.  - Bullshit.
沒錯，是胡扯，她死了，她又活了
Bullshit's right. She's dead and then she's alive.
我要說的就是這個意思，非常麻煩的案子
That's what I'm talking about. It's very fucking complicated.
但我還是繼續查了
But I persevere, you know.
我調監控來看了一遍，心想
I run the tape through and I think,
也許真有個姑娘出現過
"Okay, maybe there was a girl there."
艾蜜莉雅？老太太看見的是艾蜜莉雅？
Amelia? The old lady saw Amelia?
聽了半天你終於開竅了啊，沒錯
Well, look who decided to show up for class. Yeah.
那有個門衛
There's a gate guard,
記錄所有進出的車輛
he keeps track of all the cars that go in and out.
我就找他對了下
So I checked with him,
記下了車牌號，查明了車主身份
I ran the plate, I got the name.
然後呢？
And?
三，三啥玩意?
Three. Three what?
要想知道後面的事
Three days in advance
先支付我3天的報酬
if you want the rest of the story.
你少來了，居然要600塊？簡直就是搶錢啊
Fuck you. Come on, $600? That's fucking robbery.
我只有400
I've only got $400.
現在天色還早
Well, it's early.
你動作快點去搶銀行還來得及
You can go rob a bank if you hurry.
天啊
Jesus!
- 你跑來幹嘛？  - 給你表演鼓連擊
- What are you doing here?  - Giving you a rim job.
什麼？是鼓邊擊(爵士鼓技巧)
What? Rim shot.
- 鼓邊擊  - 管他的呢
- Rim shot.  - HOLLY: Whatever.
嘿，我們可以再玩一局嗎...
Hey, can we go one more game before...
你不就是那個海扁我爸的人嗎
You're the guy who beat up my dad.
- 嘿  - 不對，是偷襲你爸
- Hey.  - No. Sucker-punched your dad.
差別很大的，不過別擔心
Big difference. But don't worry.
他只是拿人錢財、替人消災而已
He just did it for money.
你靠海扁別人來賺錢？
You beat people up and charge money?
對，很可悲，是吧？
Yeah. Sad, isn't it?
- 你真的是幹這個的？  - 沒錯
- That's really your job?  - Yeah.
- 不可能吧  - 是真的
- No way.  - Yeah.
那我要出多少錢
So, um, how much would you charge
能請你去教訓我的朋友珍妮特？
to beat up my friend Janet?
- 什麼？  - 你有多少?
- What?  - How much you got?
- 30塊  - 瞧，這有蘋果派
- 30 bucks.  - Look, apple pie.
- 她身材高大？ - 她很高，超級煩人
- JACKSON: Is she a big girl?  - She's tall. Super annoying.
- 快吃蘋果派  - 她總是針對我
- HOLLAND: Apple pie.  - She's always mean to me.
好了，談話到此結束
This conversation is over.
- 我們只是閒談而已  - 沒什麼好談的了
- We're just talking.  - And it's over.
400塊，就這麼多
JACKSON: $400, that's all.
400塊2天
$400, two days.
要是我們提前找到她，錢還是全收
We find her earlier, I still get to keep it.
- 成交  - 成交，太好了
- Done.  - HOLLAND: Deal. Great.
因為我已經知道她在哪了
'Cause I already know where she is.
成人影星米絲蒂·芒滕絲
JACKSON: Adult film star Misty Mountains,
出席了上個月的底特律汽車展
shown here at last month's Detroit auto show.
你手裡備受關注的案子，對吧？
High-profile case for you, right?
報紙都報導了
Made the newspapers.
你知道嗎，讓你閉嘴的目的
You know, the thing about keeping your mouth closed is
就是讓你講不了話
it prevents you from speaking.
的確
Sure.
除非你是腹語者
Unless, of course, you're a ventriloquist.
那是幫騙子
Fuck those guys.
你總能看見他們的嘴在動
You can always see their mouths moving.
什麼？
You can what?
腹語根本就不可能
Ventriloquism, it doesn't work.
有例外的
Sometimes.
絕不可能
Never.
- 瞧這一幫子蠢貨  - 加入我們吧
- Look at these idiots.  - MAN: Join us.
好了
All right. Well...
- 再見了  - 嘿，嘿，等一等
- Goodbye.  - Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hold on.
你說再見是什麼意思？
What do you mean, goodbye?
這是艾蜜莉雅的抗議隊伍
This is Amelia's protest group.
她就在這裡面，所以嘛，自己去找吧
She's in there somewhere, so have at it.
等下，你怎麼知道她就在這裡面？
Wait. How do you know she's in there?
因為這就是她的抗議隊伍，是她組織的
'Cause it's her protest group. She started it.
我昨天剛好得到這條重要線索，就在你擰斷我手臂之前
That's the hot tip I got yesterday before you broke my arm.
好，但她會躲在某個藏身之所吧
Yeah, but she's holed up somewhere hiding.
你憑什麼認為她會出現在這？
What makes you think she's gonna be here?
- 這是她的抗議隊伍  - 別再重複這句話了
- That's her protest group.  - Stop saying that.
- 我也不想說的  - 別再重複了
- I'd like to stop saying...  - You said that.
我聽見了，這是她的抗議隊伍
I hear it. It's her protest group.
我沒聽見你喊啊
I don't hear you hearing it.
嘿，艾蜜莉雅
Hey, Amelia?
- 艾蜜莉雅？  - 艾蜜莉雅？
- Amelia?  - Amelia?
- 她不在這  - 她在這
- She's not here.  - She's here.
- 艾蜜莉雅  - 我們沒法跟你說話
- Amelia.  - WOMAN: We can't talk to you.
誰說的？
Who said that?
我們沒法跟你說話，我們已經死了
We can't talk to you. We're dead.
沒有，我...
No, I...
好，我明白
Yeah, I get it, you know.
這麼做好像很聰明，我也趕時髦的
Like it's very clever. I'm hip.
可這是件很重要的事情
But this is actually a really serious matter.
我們的也一樣，我們都被殺死了
So is this. We've all been killed.
- 沒有，你們沒死   - 去你媽的，我們都死了
- No, you haven't.  - Fuck you, man. We're dead.
他們沒法跟你說話，他們都死了
They can't talk to you, man.  They're dead.
他們抗議什麼呢，你知道嗎？
What's the protest about? Do you know?
你們當中有誰知道抗議原因嗎？
Any of you know why you're protesting?
- 空氣  - 空氣
- The air.  - Air.
- 你們在抗議空氣？  - 空氣污染
- You're protesting the air?  - The pollution.
鳥兒都窒息了
The birds can't breathe.
所以你們都是因為空氣污染而死的？
So all of you died because of the pollution?
是的
Right.
那防毒面具是做什麼用的，沒能救你一命？
What about the gas masks? They didn't save you?
這簡直太... 好吧
This is fucking... All right.
- 混球  - 對不起
- Fucker.  - HOLLAND: Sorry.
我以為你死了呢
I thought you were dead.
聽著，艾蜜莉雅，我們知道你在這
Look, Amelia, we know you're here,
所以...
so this is very...
嘿，混蛋，她不在這裡
Hey, dickhead. She's not here.
她因為男朋友的事所以沒來
WOMAN: She's not here because of her boyfriend.
她男朋友死了
Her boyfriend died,
是真的死了，3天前的事
like really died, like three days ago.
- 她男朋友死了?  - 沒錯
- HOLLAND: Her boyfriend died?  - Yeah.
那她在哪？
So where is she?
抱歉，幫不到你，我們都死了
Sorry, can't help you. We're dead.
天殺的
God damn it.
好吧，你們當中有哪個衰人想賺20塊的？
All right, which one of you cock and balls wants to make 20 bucks, huh?
- 走這邊，切特？  - 恩，前面左轉
- Up here, Chet?  - Yeah, make a left here.
就是這了，靠邊停
It's here. Just... Just pull over.
就是這，路左邊
It's right here. On the left.
瞧左邊
Right... Look. Left.
就是這裡
Right here.
這是迪安的房子
This is Dean's house.
艾蜜莉雅的男朋友，迪安
Amelia's boyfriend, Dean.
你不是開玩笑吧
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
是啊，難以置信
I know, it's crazy.
這他媽是怎麼一回事，切特？
What the fuck is this, Chet?
這地方現在感覺寬敞多了
This place looks so much bigger now.
你真的認識艾蜜莉雅嗎，切特？
Do you even really know Amelia, Chet?
呃，其實是迪安介紹我們認識的
Uh, yeah, well, like kind of like mainly through Dean.
迪安是拍電影的
Dean was a film-maker. Um...
喜歡拍那種實驗性電影
Kind of like experimental kinds of films. Um...
也正是這點愛好，才讓我倆認識的
That's actually like kind of how we met,
因為我自己也是電影從業人員
'cause I'm kind of in the business myself.
- 你是做什麼的？  - 電影放映師
- Huh? What do you do?  - Projectionalist.
總之，迪安有間房
Yeah, anyway, um, Dean had
裡面堆滿了電影膠片
this whole room like filled with film stock.
有一天突然就燒了起來
One day it just went up, you know...
他因此送了命，一生的心血也付之一炬
And, uh, yeah, it cost the guy his life and his life's work.
不禁
So, kind of, I don't know,
不禁讓你感慨
kind of makes you think, right?
不見得，切特
Not really, Chet.
嘿，小孩，小孩
Hey, kid. Kid.
什麼事？
What?
你認識住這的人嗎？
You know the guy who lived here?
也許，你問這幹嘛？
Maybe. What's it to you?
你肯回答的話，他會給你20塊錢
Hey, he'll give you $20 if you answer.
我可沒這樣說過
I didn't say that.
拿20塊來，不然就滾蛋
20 bucks, man, or you can blow.
哇
Wow.
謝啦
Thank you.
恩，我認識這哥們
Yeah, I knew the dude.
拍電影的哥們
Film-maker dude.
上個月還看見他拍電影呢
Saw him making a film last month.
實驗性電影，對吧？
Experimental films, right?
說不準，更像是色情電影
I guess. More like a nudie film.
你看沒看見一個5尺8、黑頭發的姑娘，叫艾蜜莉雅的
Did you see a girl about 5'8", dark hair, named Amelia?
沒
Nope.
- 只看見了那個女明星  - 哪個女明星？
- Saw that famous chick.  - What famous chick?
死了的那個，色情片女星，米絲蒂什麼的
Dead one. Porn star. Misty something.
- 你看見米絲蒂·芒滕絲了？  - 恩
- You saw Misty Mountains here?  - Yeah.
跟製片人搞在一起
Talked to the producer.
那人叫錫德... 錫德·海瑞克
No, his name was Sid... Sid Hatrack. Yeah.
- 沒有海瑞克這個姓  - 無所謂，我想找他要個角色
- Nobody's name is Hatrack.  - Whatever. Tried to get a job.
提出給他看看我的老二，因為我老二很大的
I offered to show my dick 'cause I got a big dick.
- 好了  - 恩
- Oh, right.  - Yeah.
- 你答得挺好  - 恩
- Well, that's very nice.  - Yeah.
你確認沒見著其他的姑娘？
You sure you didn't see another girl?
沒有，你們想瞧瞧我的老二嗎？
Nope. You guys wanna see my dick?
沒人想瞧你的老二，小子
Nobody wants to see your dick, dude.
- 20塊？  - 我們已經付給你20塊了...
- 20 bucks?  - We already paid you 20...
- 我還廢什麼話啊  - 那好吧
- What am I saying?  - Oh, all right.
一幫基佬
Fags!
嘿，小子
Hey, kid.
什麼？
What?
那部電影叫什麼名字？
What was the name of that film?
記不清了
I don't know. Uh...
“你喜歡我的車嗎？大男孩”
How Do You Like My Car, Big Boy?
好像是的
There it is.
“你想瞧瞧我的老二嗎”，這都什麼人啊
"Do you wanna see my dick?"  Unbelievable.
這就和我想的一樣
This is what I'm talking about.
都結束了
It's over.
相敬如賓的時代一去不返了
The days of ladies and gentlemen are over.
這就是霍莉將來要面對的
This is what Holly's looking down the barrel of.
她以後要打交道的就是
This is what she's dealing with,
切特這種貨色，還有那個低能兒
the fucking Chets and that idiot.
我唯一敢肯定的就是
JACKSON: Well, one thing we know for sure,
這裡面有些蹊蹺啊
something funny's going on.
哪有啊，火災死人這種事，很平常啊
No, it's not. No. A guy burned up. It happens.
這是3天前發生的事
It happened three days ago,
剛好是艾蜜莉雅從我雷達上消失的時候
the exact same day Amelia fell off my radar.
你雷達？
Your radar?
讓我給你解釋下偵探2天的工作是個什麼樣子
Let me tell you what two days of detective work looks like, okay?
你開著車到處亂竄
You drive around like an asshole.
花一半的時間
You're gonna spend half the time
詢問那些和切特一樣的貨色
interviewing the fucking Chets of the world.
另一半的時間你都在儘量說好話不發飆
You spend the other half trying to translate fuckwit to English.
等一切結束，唯一的收穫就是
And when it's over, the only thing that's changed
又浪費了2天時間
is that the sun went down twice.
你想說忙活半天都是瞎忙？
And nothing ever works out, is that what you're trying to say?
- 從來都是的  - 可你有錢賺啊
- Never.  - But you get paid.
有時吧
Sometimes.
嘿
Hey.
這你媽的
Son of a bitch.
海瑞克
Hatrack.
- 什麼？  - 海瑞克，快看那個
- What?  - Hatrack. Look at that.
什麼？
What?
錫德·沙特克，那是誰啊？
Sid Shattuck. Who's that?
“野人”錫德，色情片皇帝
HOLLAND: Savage Sid, the porn king.
他可沒被燒死，那我們去找他談談吧
Well, he didn't burn up, so let's go talk to him.
我說我想跟錫德親自談談
I said I'd like to speak to Sid personally.
我想找下我們共同的朋友，艾蜜莉雅
I'm asking after a friend of ours, Amelia.
我和她是老友
I'm an old friend.
為什麼我們不邀請他進來?
Why don't we invite him in?
野獸不得入內，寶貝
No animals in the house, sweetheart.
恩，我還在
Yeah, I'm here.
再說一遍？
Say that again.
好吧，非常感謝
Okay. Thank you very much.
你問到錫德·沙特克的號碼了？
Is that the number you got for Sid Shattuck?
恩，你能掛下電話嗎？
Yeah. Can you hang this up?
他們正準備參加派對，我問到艾蜜莉雅時
They're getting ready for a party and I asked about Amelia
他們說她馬上就回來
and they said she'd be right back.
回來？這麼說她就在那裡嘍
Back? Like she's been staying there?
沒錯
Yeah.
- 那你就找到她了啊  - 也許吧
- So you found her?  - Maybe.
你可以去你朋友家嗎？
Can you stay at one of your friends'?
我可以去潔西嘉家，不過...
I can stay with Jessica, but...
- 你要去參加派對？  - 不
- You're going to a party?  - No.
我要去參加一個盛大的派對，夾克給我
I'm going to a big party. Jacket.
寶貝，這是工作需要，我必須參加
Sweetheart, it's a job. I gotta take it.
我不參加的話，我們就住不起這麼好的房子了
If I don't, we won't get to live in such a nice house.
我討厭這房子
I hate this house.
我們根本不該住在這裡的
We're not even supposed to be here.
- 去珍妮特家  - 潔西嘉家
- Go to Janet's.  - Jessica's.
- 她是哪一個？  - 褐色頭髮的
- Which one's she?  - The one with the brown hair.
- 呆呆的那個？  - 你喜歡哪個？
- Glass eye?  - The one that you like.
有希特勒的鬍子的
And like the Hitler-stache?
我交了一個員警朋友
I'm friends with a cop, you know.
- 這樣啊？  - 他也很喜歡我爸爸
- Is that so?  - He likes my dad a lot, too.
也許他們該結婚
Maybe they should get married.
那麼你認識這個老太太？
JACKSON: So, you know the old lady, right?
- 你相信她嗎？  - 關於什麼？
- Did you believe her?  - What about?
她說她那晚看見米絲蒂活著時
When she said she saw Misty alive that night,
你相信她嗎？
did you believe her?
老天，當然不信，她瞎得跟蝙蝠似的
God, no. She's blind as a bat.
哦
JACKSON: Uh-huh.
她帶的老花鏡就和可樂瓶底一般厚
She has actual coke bottles for glasses.
你要是給大眾車畫上鬍子，她看到肯定會說
You paint a moustache on a Volkswagen, she says,
“那奧瑪·沙裡夫跑得可真快啊”（著名演員）
"Boy, that Omar Sharif sure runs fast."
踢踏的老天爺啊
Jesus tap-dancing Christ!
我就這麼回復他的，你要是想讓我做那種事
All I told him was that if you want me to do that,
就別吃蘆筍好嗎
then don't eat the asparagus.
為什麼？
GIRL: Why?
我知道你要說些什麼，可是我來都來了
I know what you're gonna say, but since I'm already here,
你乾脆就帶我一起進去吧，行不行？
you might as well take me in with you, right?
呃，這種情況我是不能收你車的
Um, I can't take your car like that.
- 住手  - 什麼？
-Stop it.  - What?
住手，停下，爸爸
Stop it. Stop it. Dad.
爸爸，這裡有好多小姐什麼的
Dad, there's like whores here and stuff.
寶貝，我跟你講過多少次了
Sweetheart, how many times have I told you?
別用“什麼的”
Don't say "and stuff."
直接說，“爸爸，這裡有好多小姐啊”
Just say, "Dad, there are whores here."
這成群結隊的... 別這樣，我能幫你的忙
Well, there's like a ton. Wait. No. I can help you.
這麼遠我都挨過來了，真要我走啊？
Seriously? I came all this way.
我愛你
I love you.
你還記得
Do you remember
九月 - 大地風火
9月21日的晚上嗎？
the 21st night of September?
愛不但驅散了雲霧
Love was changing the minds of pretenders
也讓偽裝者認真起來
While chasing the clouds away
變長的可不是我的鼻子
It's not my nose that grows.
我們的心在靈魂
Our hearts were ringing
歌唱的節奏下為之顫動
In the key that our souls were singing.
呵呵，我看麻人精肯定登場了
Whoa. Well, we know Mary Jane turned up.
- 那是誰？  - 麻人精，大麻啊
- Who's that?  - Mary Jane. Marijuana. Pot.
這麼大的味，很多人都在抽
Place reeks of it. They're smoking it.
- 沒錯，不過我聞不到  - 什麼？
- Oh, yeah. I can't smell.  - What?
前陣子我撞到頭
I got hit in the head a while back.
喪失了嗅覺
I lost my sense of smell.
你聞不到？
You can't smell?
- 恩  - 嗷
- Yeah.  - Wow.
都聞不到，你還做私家偵探？
You're a detective who can't smell?
對
Yeah.
呵，這真是越來越有意思了
Oh, this just keeps getting better and better.
你還真是沒一點同情心啊
Wow, that's really insensitive.
要是艾蜜莉雅沒有現身
HOLLAND: Look, if Amelia doesn't show,
我們還有沙特克，對吧？
we still got Shattuck, right?
要是起了衝突，我受了傷的
But if things get rough, I'm injured.
- 所以你得出面應付  - 好
-So you're gonna have to handle it.  -JACKSON: Right.
你可以拿他的兒子做人質，什麼招都行
Well, you know, blind his son, or, you know, whatever it is.
你儘管使出來，你要去哪？
You work your magic. Where you going?
我覺得分頭行動的話會更好些，也能快些
I think this is gonna work better, faster, if we split up.
- 好嗎？  - 什麼？
- Okay?  - What?
要是你見到一個藍臉的傢伙
You see a guy with a blue face,
就趕緊來找我
you come and find me.
你要煙嗎？
WOMAN: You wanna smoke?
或者喝點啥？
Drink?
不用了，我...
No, I...
嘿，對不起
Hey, uh... Sorry.
殺人蜂
It's the killer bees.
你一定要小心這東西
That's what you gotta worry about.
你知道它們為什麼被稱作“殺人蜂”吧?
You know why they call them killer bees, don't you?
- 因為它們能殺了你  - 說得很對
- 'Cause they'll kill you.  - HOLLAND: Good point.
- 打擾了  - 你好啊，帥哥
- Excuse me.  - Hello, handsome.
你站的地方好像視野開闊
You, uh, seem to have a very good vantage point up there.
- 我跟妹妹走散了  - 嗯？
- I lost my sister.  - GIRL: Yeah.
她是黑髮，和你身高差不多
She's got dark hair, your height.
她穿著衣服
She's wearing clothes, but...
快點，美人，接著跳啊
MAN: Come on, baby, keep dancing!
名字是艾蜜莉雅
HOLLAND: Answers to Amelia.
嘿，再來一杯？別去騷擾小姐
Hey. You want another drink? Just leave the girl alone.
“你喜歡我的車嗎，大男孩？”   米絲蒂，第一幕
- 嗨，你們好  - 嘿
- Hi, everyone.  - WOMAN: Hey.
我是艾蜜莉雅，她大約是黑髮
I'm Amelia. She's about dark hair.
名字是野性的呼喚
Answers to the call of the wild.
- 開個玩笑  - 什麼？
- I'm just kidding.  - WOMAN: What?
我忘了她的名字了，你要是看見你的話
I forgot her name, but, you know, if you see you,
你要是看見了，告訴我一聲，告訴我叫什麼
just if you see, let me know and tell me my name.
米絲蒂，試拍片段，第一卷
- 抱歉  - 謝謝
- Sorry.  - Thank you.
- 要來杯酒嗎?   - 不了，謝謝
- You want a drink?  - No, thanks.
嗷
WOMAN: Ow!
霍莉，嘿
Holly. Hey, hey.
我覺得你不該看這種東西
I don't think you should be watching this.
關你什麼事，白癡，讓開別擋著我
What's it to you, idiot? Move. You're in my way.
聽好了，傻逼，那小女孩還未成年
Listen, dickweed, that little girl's a minor.
你怎麼可以放這種片子給她看
Where do you get off showing her stuff like this anyway?
又不是他放給我看的
He's not showing it to me.
是她放的
She put it on.
她也不該看這種片子啊
Well, she shouldn't be watching stuff like this either.
看？大哥，就是我演的片子啊
Watching it? Man, I'm in it.
哦，好吧，回家好嗎？
Oh, right. Look, go home, right?
你爸不是讓你回家嗎？快回去吧
Your dad told you to go home. Go home.
順便說下，我來這是要找個人
By the way, I'm supposed to meet someone here.
你或許認識一個叫艾蜜莉雅的？
Do you by any chance know a girl named Amelia?
我聽說她和錫德·沙特克拍了個片子
I think she did a film with Sid Shattuck.
我不認識她，不過錫德噁心死了
Don't know her, but Sid's gross.
他有次告訴我一個小妞是他妹妹
He told me this one chick was his sister, right,
然後過了幾天，我剛好撞見他倆
and then a few days later I walk in on them
他們都在玩肛交什麼的
and they're all doing anal and stuff.
別說“什麼的”
Don't say, "and stuff."
直接說他們在玩肛交就行了
Just say, "They're doing anal."
嘿，寶嘉康蒂
WOMAN: Hey, Pocahontas!
- 嘿  - 我是牛仔
- Hey.  - I'm a cowboy.
- 你呢?  - 寶嘉康蒂
- And you?  - Pocahontas.
- 你是做什麼的？  - 演過些片子
- What do you do?  - I do a little bit of acting.
- 我也是，嘿，開槍打我  - 什麼？
- Me, too. Hey, shoot me.  - What?
開槍打我，打我啊
Shoot me, shoot me, shoot me. Fucking shoot me.
梆
Bang!
演的不錯
That's pretty good.
- 梆  - 啊
- Bang!  - Oh.
梆
Bang!
你媽的個...
Son of a...
哇噢，你演的太棒了
Whoo! That was great!
媽的
Shit.
Shit!
槍不見了
My fucking gun.
天啊
Jesus.
你嚇我一跳
You scared me.
我認識你嗎？
Do I know you?
我不會傷害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
我只是在找我的槍而已
No, I'm just looking for my gun.
所以...
So...
我找到了
I got it!
所以...
So...
幹得好，馬奇
There you go, March.
馬奇，馬奇，他能行的，他辦不成的事，別人就更不行了
March, March, he's our man. If he can't do it, no one can.
馬奇
March.
希利... 希利
Healy. Healy!
希利
Healy!
快來，快點下來
Come on. Come down here.
你怎麼跑那底下去了？
What the fuck are you doing down there?
趕緊下來
Get down here!
- 希利  - 沒事的，夥計
- Healy!  - It's all right, man.
怎麼了？
What?
- 我操  - 我覺得噁心，想吐
- Oh, fuck.  - I'm gonna be sick, throw up.
唔
Oh.
這他媽是誰啊？
Who the fuck is that?
是錫德·沙特克
It's Sid Shattuck.
- 那是錫德·沙特克  - 不是吧
- That's Sid Shattuck.  - Don't tell me that.
怎麼會這樣，媽的
Oh, no. Shit!
- 到底是怎麼回事？  - 媽的
- What's going on?  - Shit!
這都是和艾蜜莉雅合作的人，對吧？
Everybody worked on this Amelia flick, right?
她男朋友，然後米絲蒂
The boyfriend, then Misty,
現在是錫德，他們全死了
now Sid. They're all dead.
在我們解決世紀大案之前
Before we go solving the crime of the century,
先要處理掉這具腐爛的屍體啊
let's deal with the fucking rotting corpse.
我們該怎麼處理這傢伙？
What the fuck are we gonna do with this guy?
- 我們得扔掉他   - 為什麼？
- We gotta get rid of him.  - Why?
我剛弄丟了槍
I lost my gun.
然後那跑出個姑娘，她可以指證我
There was a girl. She can place me.
好吧，我們這麼辦吧
All right, we got a plan.
先吐乾淨，然後找地方把屍體扔掉
We'll throw up, we'll get rid of the body.
好的
Right.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- Hey.  - Hi.
就是你在找艾蜜莉雅？
Are you the one who's been asking about Amelia?
我可能隨便問了下
Uh, I may have said something.
你找她幹嘛？
What do you want with her?
她是我姐姐
Um, she's my sister, see.
嗯，我來這是要她提防著點
Yeah, um, I need to warn her.
有兩個可疑的傢伙在找她
Two freaky guys were coming around.
不斷詢問她的下落
They were all like, "Where is she? Where is she?"
這讓我有些害怕
It scared me kinda.
你像是個誠實的孩子
Well, you seem like a decent kid.
我帶你去找她吧
I'll take you to her.
- 走吧  - 好的
- Come on.  - Okay.
我想不通的是，你離他那麼遠
What I can't figure out is how you saw him
怎麼可能看得到他？
from all the way up there.
你不是滾下山了吧，是不是？
You didn't fall down the fucking hill, did you?
你滾下山了？
Did you fall down the hill?
我多喝了幾杯
I had like two, three drinks, tops.
嗯，所以你路都走不穩了
Yeah, that's why you can't walk straight.
不好意思，我可抬著具死屍
Oh, excuse me. I'm carrying a dead body
他的老二正對著我
and I have his schwantz in my face.
很抱歉我不能像巴克什尼科夫般輕盈
So, I'm sorry I'm not Bakishnarov.
你連巴雷什尼科夫的名字都說不對（芭蕾舞男星）
You can't even say Baryshnikov.
你滾下來了，是不是？
You did, didn't you?
你個衰人滾下了山
You fell down that fucking hill.
你喝高了，弄丟了槍
You get drunk, you lose your gun,
從陽臺倒載了下去
you take a header off the balcony
你現在還想告訴我
and now you're gonna tell me
這就是神探
it's like a hallowed,
破案的手法？
time-honoured detective ploy, right?
那上面很滑，好嗎？
It was very slippery up there, okay?
我先前在泳池裡
I was... I was in the pool.
- 你在泳池裡？  - 是的
- You were in the pool?  - Yeah.
為什麼？
Why?
我得詢問下美人魚
I had to question the mermaids.
我忙著幹活時你幹什麼去了？
What were you doing while I was working?
- 沒話說了？  - 讓我們扔掉這傢伙
- Thank you.  - Let's get rid of this guy.
天啊
HOLLAND: Oh, God.
天啊，我的腿，我的腿
Oh, God! My leg! My leg!
那是什麼？
WOMAN: What is that?
快跑
JACKSON: Run.
坐到後座上，小可愛
Hop in back, sweetie.
這位聲稱是艾蜜莉雅的妹妹
This one says she's Amelia's sister.
是真的嗎？
Is that a fact?
好玩了
Good times.
我... 外面有人在找我
I... There's someone out looking for me.
- 真的  - 嗯，我...
BLUEFACE: Really?  HOLLY: Yeah. I...
嘿，嘿，別碰那個
Hey, hey, hey. No. Don't touch that.
嘿，你為什麼不來看我的影片？
Hey. Why didn't you watch my movie?
- 嘿，再見  - 來和我一起看啊
- JACKSON: Hey, goodbye.  - Come and watch with me.
- 你玩的開心點  - 來嘛，還沒放完呢
- Have a great night.  - Come on. It's still playing.
玩的開心點，再見
Have a great night. Bye.
讓下，請讓下
HOLLAND: Excuse me. Excuse me.
- 我得走了  - 別碰...
- I need to go right now.  - BLUEFACE: Don't touch...
別碰我
HOLLY: Get away from me.
給我鑰匙，和我的車
AMELIA: I need my keys. I need my car.
快點
Hurry.
給老子坐好
Don't fucking move.
快點，我的車鑰匙呢?
AMELIA: Hurry. I need my keys.
請你快點好嗎，快點
Hello? Please! Hurry, hurry.
馬上給我
Now!
操，操你媽的，我的手
Fuck! Motherfucker, my fucking hand!
艾蜜莉雅，快跑
Amelia! Run!
趕緊給老子開車
Drive the fucking car.
嘿，大哥
Hey, man.
你後備箱裡的那個女孩，她也在那輛車裡
The girl in your trunk, she was in that car.
那是約翰尼的車
MAN: Johnny's car!
嘿，你動我的車幹嘛？
JOHNNY: Hey, man, what are you doing with my car?
狗日的
Motherfucker!
媽的
MAN: Oh, shit.
我對天發誓，你敢起來的話，我就打爆你的老二
I swear to God, you get up, I'll shoot you in the cock.
我可以給你錢
I can pay you.
想跟我談條件？
Trying to negotiate with me?
你不會再見到我了
You'll never see me again.
你要去哪？
Where are you gonna be?
- 密西根  - 密西根行啊
- Michigan.  - Michigan works.
你沒事吧？車還能開嗎？
You okay? Does the car still go?
別浪費時間，快點追
Well, stop fucking around. Come on.
我操...
Fuck!
站住
Freeze!
你們跑得可真快啊
You guys are fast.
唔
Whoo!
有輛...
There's a...
天啊
DRIVER: Holy shit!
- 快走  - 等等
- Come on.  - Wait. Wait.
你想幹什麼呢？
AMELIA: What the hell are you doing?
他受傷了，我們得去幫幫他
HOLLY: He's hurt. We need to help him.
你瘋了嗎，離他遠點
Are you crazy? Stay away from him.
先等下，我們不能見死不救
Just... Just hang on. We need to help him.
沒事的
It's okay.
你會沒事的，我找人來幫你
You're gonna be all right. I'll... I'll get help.
沒事的
It's all right.
他被車撞了，我們得叫救護車
A car hit him. We need an ambulance.
霍莉，你去看看能不能攔輛車
Holly, go and see if you can flag somebody down.
他傷得很重
He's in a bad way.
是你
You.
沒錯，是我
Yeah, me.
你聽說過約翰·博伊嗎
You ever hear of John Boy?
他現在肯定知道你了
By now he's heard of you.
他們派他過來了
They're flying him in.
他會先幹掉那個私家偵探
Now he's gonna kill that private cop
還有他的家人
and his whole fucking family.
之後他就會來收拾你了
And then he's gonna come for you.
你時間不多了
You ain't got long to live.
可是夥計
Well, buddy,
你也是一樣的
none of us do.
- 希利，下面根本就沒人  - 他沒能撐下去
- Healy, there's no one here.  - He didn't make it.
- 你沒事吧?  - 恩
- Are you okay?  - Yeah.
下面就交給員警了
And that'll be the cops.
好了，霍利
MAN: Okay, Holly...
你要我怎麼處理他們？
OFFICER: What do you want me to do with them?
夥計，你已經有了我倆的證詞
Look, pal, you already got our statements.
可以讓我去見女兒了嗎？
Can I go see my daughter now?
先生，上面要我在這看著你倆
Sir, I was told to keep you here,
所以我只能照辦
so I'm keeping you here.
服從命令而已
Just following orders.
你知道還有誰也是服從命令嗎？希特勒
You know who else was just following orders? Hitler.
警官
Officer.
你是馬奇先生吧
You're Mr March, I think.
這位元是，我好像認識你
And you are... Wait, I know you.
你是那個，飯店爺對吧？
You're the guy. The diner guy, right?
去年的時候，對吧？
From last year, right?
- 沒錯 - 嗯，我是塔利
- Yeah.  - Yeah. My name is Tally.
請跟我來
If you'll follow me,
我上司想找你們談談，請吧
my boss would like a word. Please.
不好意思，飯店爺？
I'm sorry. The diner guy?
先別急，我以後會告訴你的
I'll tell you later. Don't worry about it.
你們好啊
How do you do?
大部分時候都很好
About this good most of the time.
我是裘蒂斯·庫特納
My name is Judith Kuttner.
在司法部工作
I work for the Department of Justice.
好，可那就和沒說一樣
Okay. Well, that explains basically nothing.
我是艾蜜莉雅的母親
I... I'm Amelia's mother.
霍莉，你還皺著眉頭啊？
TALLY: Holly, are you still frowning?
看看我手裡是什麼？
What's in my hand?
厲害吧
What?
看看我手裡是什麼？
What's in my hand?
厲害吧
What?
我知道你怎麼變的
HOLLY: I know how you do that.
你們好
Hello.
坐下吧
Sit.
首先，我得向你們表示感謝
First of all, I wanna say thank you.
我們剛才一直在看口供
We've been watching interviews,
似乎你倆救了我女兒一命
and it sounds like you might have saved my daughter's life.
都是霍莉的功勞
That was mostly Holly.
- 他閨女  - 這是遺傳的
- His daughter.  - It's genetics.
你要來點薄荷嗎?
Would you like a mint?
好的
Uh, yeah.
我需要你們幫忙
JUDITH: I need your help.
不過我得先確認你倆是否可靠
But I wanna know if I can trust you.
我倒是覺得
I'm kinda getting the idea that, you know,
你好像沒得選擇啊
you might not have much choice.
是的，我的處境很微妙
Well, my situation is very delicate.
哦，我想起來了，在電視上看到過你
Hey, that's where I know you from, right? The TV.
你正辦那起汽車廠商的案子
You're prosecuting that car company thing.
針對尾氣淨化器的訴訟
The lawsuit for the catalytic converter.
沒錯，我工作有一半時間都花在那上面
Yes. That's half my day.
另一半時間我花在色情電影上
The other half I spend on pornography.
什麼類型的，哪部電影
What kind? Like which films?
哪些是你的最愛？
What's your favourite?
不，你想錯了，抵制，抵制色情電影
No, no. Uh, anti. Anti-porn.
- 對  - 就像改革家
- Right.  - Like a crusader.
我該把這些都記下來嗎？
Should I be writing this down?
恩，記下來吧
JACKSON: Yeah, write it down.
賭城的黑幫想把他們的色情產業
The Vegas mob is trying to spread its porn operation
擴張到好萊塢大道
to Hollywood Boulevard.
我正竭力阻止這發生
And I'm doing everything I can to stop it.
謝謝
Thank you.
色情業是毒瘤
Porn is bad.
我不明白的是，你女兒
Something I don't understand. Your daughter,
她跟錫德·沙特克拍了一部電影
she did a film with Sid Shattuck.
她為什麼要這樣做？她應該明白
Now, why would she do that when she knows that's just gonna be
這是對你職業的極大侮辱
extremely professionally embarrassing for you?
因為這就是她的初衷，她跟我鬧翻了
'Cause she wanted to. She lashes out.
我們一直關係緊張
We have a difficult relationship.
母女關係，總是個難題
Mothers and daughters, it's tough.
不過影片沒了，不存在了，發生了一場火災
But there's no film, not any more. There was a fire.
- 艾蜜莉雅的一個朋友  - 迪恩
- A friend of Amelia's, he...  - Dean.
恩，我們去過他的房子
Yeah, we went to his house.
燒成一片廢墟
Well, what's left of his house.
庫特納女士，和這部電影有關的人
Mrs Kuttner, why do you think
一個接一個的死，你是怎麼看的？
everyone involved with this film is dying?
我完全沒有頭緒，馬奇先生，我要知道就好了
I have no idea, Mr March. I wish I did.
我只知道艾蜜莉雅現在有危險
I only know that Amelia's in danger.
你為什麼不給她申請保護性拘留呢？
Why don't you put her in protective custody?
我覺得，今晚發生的事，她肯定被嚇得不輕
I mean, after tonight, she's probably very scared.
她也許想回家
She... She might wanna be at home.
她不信任我
She doesn't trust me.
她認為我就代表政府
She thinks I am the government.
她認為這一切都是我指使的
She thinks I'm behind all of this.
她現在躲在外面，也不給家裡電話
Somewhere she's out there and she won't call home
因為她認為我這個當媽的要找人謀害她
because she thinks her mother's going to have her killed.
你需要這個嗎？
Here. You wanna use that?
不用，謝謝
No, thank you.
我想雇傭你們倆
I wanna hire you both.
請你們找到她，保護好她
Please, find her, protect her.
好，你可以雇我們，不過我們可不便宜
Okay, you can hire us, but we're not cheap.
這活要求的工作量可不小
This is very intensive work and something like this,
我覺得，報酬最少也要五千塊吧
I'd say couldn't do it for less than $5,000.
一萬
我覺得，報酬最少也要五千塊吧
I'd say couldn't do it for less than $5,000.
好吧
JUDITH: Okay.
- 哈，我猜對了  - 好，換我來了
- Yes, I got it.  - Okay, I gotta get mine now.
- 我能拿張這個嗎？  - 可以
- Can I take this?  - Fine.
塔利有嗎？我們是不是也需要張她的?
Does Tally have one of... Shall we have hers as well?
只是以防萬一，你不在...
Just in case you're not...
我們也有個人能聯繫
You know, we need to get in touch with somebody.
這是搞什麼？世界上最大的煙灰缸嗎？
So what's this? World's biggest ashtray?
管他的呢，反正是租的房子
Fuck it, it's... It's a rental.
只是暫時住下，等原來的家重建好我們就會搬走
We're only here until we rebuild the old place anyway.
- 重建？ - 對
- Rebuild?  - Yeah.
原來的房子燒掉了
It burned down.
嘿，有件事我一直想不通
Hey, you know, something's actually bugging me.
這是我在沙特克的辦公室裡找到的
I found this in Shattuck's office.
那是什麼，一頭豬？
What is that, a pig?
- 不是，是粉色的奶牛  - 哦，是頭牛啊
- No, it's a pink cow.  - Oh, it's a cow.
艾蜜莉雅給我你的地址
When Amelia gave me your address,
就寫在和這一樣的紙上交給我的
she gave it to me on a piece of paper like this,
筆跡也一樣
handwriting like that.
我覺得你發現了什麼
I think you're onto something.
我們明天下午
Can we talk about it
再研究，好嗎？
tomorrow afternoon?
好，就這麼辦
Yeah, we can do that.
謝了
Thanks.
嘿，你不是那個飯店爺嗎？
Hey, aren't you that diner guy?
別害羞嘛
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
講給我聽聽
I gotta know.
我現在真不想說那件事
I don't wanna get into it right now.
你得給我分享下啊
You gotta get into it.
我想知道，你為什麼被稱作飯店爺
I gotta know. You're the diner guy.
- 好吧  - 太好了
- All right.  - Yes.
- 大概一年以前  - 好極了
- All right, about a year ago...  - Yes.
我在好萊塢的一家飯店吃飯
...I was at a diner in Hollywood
有個混球拿把散彈槍
and this asshole with a shotgun
開始嚇唬周圍的人
started threatening people.
我喜歡
HOLLAND: I love it.
這是我聽過的最有意思的故事
It's the best story I've ever heard.
我沒有袖手旁觀
JACKSON: So I did something about it.
我出了手
I acted.
我只是臨時起意
I didn't plan to, I didn't,
你懂吧
you know.
說做就做了
I just did it.
我放倒了那傢伙
I took that guy out.
根本連報酬都沒有
I didn't even get paid for it.
結果我
So I ended up
二頭肌上挨了一槍，光就醫就就花掉500大洋
with a bullet in the bicep and 500 bucks of hospital bills.
真是挺蠢的
It was stupid, really.
可後來我想了想
When I think about it,
那是我人生中最得意的一天
it was the best day of my life.
那一瞬間覺得自己有點用處
Just for a moment, I felt useful.
好了
All right.
布蘭奇小姐以前來過英格蘭嗎？
"Had Mademoiselle Blanche been in England before?
她是法國哪裡人啊？
"What part of France did she come from?
布蘭奇小姐
"Mademoiselle Blanche
禮貌的作了問答，不過有些冷淡
"replied politely but with reserve."
嘿
Hey.
你的腳踩到馬桶裡了
You've got your foot in the toilet.
真的？
I have?
現在你又弄得地毯上都是水
Now you're getting the carpet all wet.
- 這是你的房間？  - 不是，是我父母的
- Was this your room?  - No, it was Mom and Dad's.
你爸說你重新建了一個
Your dad tells me you're rebuilding.
你覺得有重建的影子嗎？
Does it look rebuilt to you?
並不覺得
Not especially.
爸爸根本就不怎麼來這，我想是覺得內疚吧
Dad barely ever comes here. He feels guilty, I guess.
為什麼？
Because?
嗯？
Hmm?
哦，因為火災的事
Oh, the fire.
媽媽一直念叨著爐灶漏氣
Mom kept on complaining about a leak in the furnace,
可我爸，他鼻子有毛病
but Dad, you know, he's got his nose thing,
所以聞不到煤氣味
so he couldn't smell the gas.
好了，我該接著讀我的書了
Anyways, I should probably get back to my book.
好吧
All right.
希利大叔
Mr Healy?
你是個壞人嗎？
Are you a bad person?
今晚的那個男人，你對他做了什麼？
What did you do to that man tonight?
你殺了他嗎？
Did you kill him?
當然沒有
Of course not.
太好了
That's good.
我就知道你不是那種人
I knew you couldn't do something like that.
別在這待太晚，好嗎？
Don't stay up too late, all right?
糟糕
Shit.
我不清楚你的表是怎麼走的
I didn't know what time you'd get here.
說好的是下午吧
You said afternoon.
呃，我們去了趟銀行，取錢給你
Well, uh, we were at the bank getting your money.
拿好，這是一半的錢，少了幾百塊
There it is, half, minus a few hundred, you know,
因為要賠償我們撞壞的那部車
for, uh, that car that we crashed.
我想你也會分擔的吧
I thought you'd wanna chip in for that.
是的
Sure.
你覺得如何？
What do you think?
- 是紫色的   - 是褐紅色
- It's purple.  - It's maroon.
我們去了酒吧，所以回來晚了
We stopped at a bar. That's why we're late.
艾蜜莉雅的便條
JACKSON: So, Amelia's note.
伯班克機場，西部航班D
Burbank Airport. Western flight D.
我認為她要逃離此地
I figure she's trying to skip town.
我們該怎麼辦？
How do you wanna do this?
我提議先等幾天，然後給庫特納電話
I don't know. I say we wait a couple of days, call Kuttner
看能不能讓她付
and see if we can squeeze
第二期款項
a second instalment out of her.
第二期款項？
A second instalment?
你別太早打電話
HOLLY: You don't wanna call too soon.
得裝出有了進展的樣子
Gotta act like you're onto something,
好像你在拼命辦案一樣
like you've been working hard.
然後，三天后，再要更多的錢
Then, day three, ask for more money.
恩，她雖然一副譏諷的口吻
Well, she's putting a negative spin on it,
不過是這個意思
but, yeah, that's the idea.
庫特納給過我們錢了
Kuttner paid us. Me.
我收了她的錢就得辦事，對吧？
She paid me to do a job, right?
- 我不會對此撒謊的  - 我尊重你的決定
- I'm not gonna lie to her.  - And I respect that.
所以就交給我辦吧
That's why I'll lie to her.
我花400塊是請偵探的
Hey, I shelled out 400 bucks for a detective.
能找出線索的那種
Someone who finds clues, huh?
那天晚上是我找到錫德·沙特克的屍體
I found Sid Shattuck's corpse, didn't I?
你找到的？你滾到他身上的
Found it? You fell on it.
我心裡搞不清楚的是，為什麼我們沒有在慶祝
I guess I don't understand why we're not celebrating.
我們不是剛賺了錢嗎
I mean, we just got paid.
應該在午後開懷暢飲啊
We're all having a drink in the afternoon.
- 咋了？  - 就當我沒說，好嗎
- What?  - Forget about it, all right?
你能...
HOLLAND: Oh, would you just...
你能稍微等幾秒鐘嗎
Would you hold on for a goddamn second?
你是這世上最差勁的偵探了
You're the world's worst detective.
- 我最差勁？  - 就是
- I'm the worst?  - Yeah.
這世上最差勁的？
The world's worst?
我剛才講得還不夠清楚嗎？
Didn't you hear me the first time?
我的廣告很酷啊
Got a cool ad, though.
所以...
So...
你為什麼總是這樣糟糕？
Why do you have to be such a fuck-up, huh?
你走到哪都是酒不離口
You go around and you drink
還老騙人什麼的，所以大家都討厭你
and you lie and stuff and people hate you.
寶貝，別說“什麼的”，就說...
Sweetheart, don't say, "and stuff." Just say...
我討厭你
I hate you!
隨你吧
That works.
我自己去找那個姑娘
I'll find the girl myself.
你找得到才怪
You're gonna find her yourself. Okay.
要真到到替我向她問好
Well, say hi to her when you do.
我會的
I will.
可是你在機場是找不到她的
Course, you're not gonna find her at the airport,
那不是航班號
seeing as how it's not a flight.
- 他停住了？  - 是的
- Did he stop?  - Yeah.
你的便條，好好瞧瞧，那不是航班資訊
Your note, look at it. It's not a flight.
每個機場都有夜間禁飛令，從晚上10點到第二天臨晨6點
Every airport has an overflight curfew from 10:00 to 6:00,
伯班克也不例外
Burbank included.
頂上的數字就是今天的日期
And that top number is today's date
不過要倒著看，就像歐洲寫法
but reversed like the European way,
這樣看就明白FLT的意思了
which makes sense when you look at FLT
那不是指航班
and you think it's not "flight,"
可能是指公寓之類的
it's probably "flat," like apartment.
那伯班克、APT、西部是指什麼？
And Burbank APT West?
伯班克公寓西區
Burbank Apartments West.
是個破地方，算了，我帶你去吧
It's a dump. Fuck it, I'll show you.
霍利，這次去珍妮特家
Holly, go to Janet's this time.
- 是真的去   - 我要去潔西嘉家
- But for real.  - Jessica's.
好吧，我們得去幹活了
Jessica's. We've gotta go to work.
- 你不拿車鑰匙嗎？  - 我來開車
- Do you want your keys?  - I'm driving.
請問下
JACKSON: Excuse me.
你知道伯班克公寓在哪嗎？
We're looking for the Burbank Apartments.
沒了
Oh, they're gone.
2年前就被拆除了
Tore them babies down, um, going on about two years now.
那就去機場吧
To the airport, then?
過去一直實施夜間禁飛的
Well, they used to have an overflight curfew.
沒啥，沒什麼的
It's all right. It's all right. It's okay.
- 真的  - 恩
- They did.  - Yeah.
應該繼續實施的，如果改了
And they still should if they changed them.
他們應該再改回來
They should, they should change them back.
- 停車  - 什麼?
- Pull over.  - What?
- 快停車  - 嘿，搞什麼啊？
- Pull over.  - Hey, what the fuck?
西部大酒店
HOLLAND: The Western Hotel.
伯班克機場西部大酒店
The Burbank Airport Western Hotel.
她可能是來見人的
She's meeting somebody.
好吧
Okay.
晚上好，兩位元需要點什麼？
Evening. What can I get you?
一點資訊，你見過這姑娘嗎？
HOLLAND: Information. Have you seen this girl?
可能半小時前來的
She probably came in in the last half hour.
夥計，我只是在這打工而已
Hey, I just work here.
就是啊，夏洛特，所以我才來問你的
Yeah, no shit, Sherlock. That's why I'm asking you.
記性這東西不好說啊
Hmm. Memory gets a little foggy, you know.
我能有什麼好處？
What's in it for me?
- 他會暫時不做某件事  - 做什麼？
- He'll stop doing it.  - Doing what?
嗷
Ow!
- 就像那樣   - 我操
- HOLLAND: That.  - Fuck!
我們可以友好協商，不然...
Now, we can do this the easy way or we can...
我們現在就是友好協商
We're currently doing it the easy way.
知道了，天啊
Okay. Jesus.
空中別墅
The penthouse.
她在空中別墅，最頂樓
She's in the penthouse, top floor.
- 你們滿意了？  - 沒錯
- Are you happy?  - HOLLAND: Yeah.
哥們，聽我一言
Guys, listen.
你們最好別上去，好嗎
You... You don't wanna go up there, all right? Trust me.
紐約來的傢伙在上面
These New York guys are up there.
那種商人
Uh, business guys.
他們帶得有保鏢的
They got fucking bodyguards.
那些人好像蛋被割掉了一樣
Kind that had their balls removed.
我忘了怎麼稱呼他們了
What's that called? Huh?
已婚人士？
Marriage?
嗯
Yeah.
就在這等會兒吧，她還會下來的
Just chill here, you know. She's gotta come back down.
我請你們喝幾杯啤酒？
Have a couple of cold ones on me?
我就算了
Oh, not for me.
他講的挺有道理
HOLLAND: He makes a strong argument, though.
你真是個通情達理的人
You see? Reasonable. Very reasonable.
可你們的夥計
Now, your buddy,
就麻煩多了，他不是講理的人
that was the problem, he wasn't reasonable.
- 我們的夥計?  - 我們可沒有其他的朋友
- Our buddy?  - Yeah, we don't have friends.
有個傢伙也在找艾蜜莉雅，他和你們不是一夥的?
The other guy looking for Amelia, he wasn't with you?
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
就在你們進來前，坐電梯走了
Got in the elevator right before you guys came in.
- 他叫什麼？  - 約翰什麼的
- Did you get a name?  - John something.
你親眼瞧見他上了電梯？
Did you actually witness him getting into the elevator?
我要是說是一個印第安長者告訴我的，你信嗎？
No, it was told to me by a wise old Indian.
當然是我親眼瞧見的啊
Of course I fucking witnessed it.
- 好  - 這到底是什麼情況？
- Right.  - What the hell's going on?
哦，我現在明白了
Oh, it just makes sense.
- 是怎麼一回事了  - 你明白什麼了？
- It connects up.  - What makes sense?
約翰·博伊，藍臉提到過的
John Boy. Oh, just something that Blueface mentioned, yeah.
你說他提到是什麼意思？
What do you mean, he mentioned?
提到啥？
Mentioned how?
就是
Oh, you know, he...
有個傢伙要來幹掉你
"There's a guy coming to kill you."
諸如此類的廢話
That kind of crap. Yeah.
我們就守在這吧？
We should probably just stay here.
明智之舉
Smart move.
除非他現在就在上面追殺她
Unless, of course, he's up there killing her right now.
沒人會被殺死在伯班克機場酒店
Nobody's getting killed at the Burbank Airport Hotel.
為什麼？
Because?
- 那會上國內新聞的  - 恩，那又如何？
- That would be national news.  - Yeah, so?
你什麼時候上過國內新聞？
Oh, so when's the last time you were on national news?
- 二月的時候  - 真的？
- February.  - Really?
- 沒錯  - 憑什麼？
- Yeah.  - For what?
- 我在飯店被槍擊的事  - 在哪啊？
- I got shot, in a diner.  - Where?
我手臂上，我昨晚不是告訴過你嗎？
In my arm. I told you this last night.
- 我們應該報警  - 不行，等員警來就晚了
- We should call the cops.  - No. It'll take too long.
她很可能就死了
I mean, she could die.
你不是說守在這是正確的做法嗎
You just said it was the right move to stay down here.
不對，我說的是明智之舉，有區別的
No, I said smart move. Different.
慕尼克
Munich.
你說什麼？
What?
沒了蛋蛋的人
A guy without his balls.
被稱作慕尼克（他想說eunuch，兩個詞發音近似）
It's a Munich.
慕尼克是德國的一座城市
Munich is a city in Germany.
又叫明興，慕尼克
München. Munich. Yeah.
知道了
Right.
希特勒只有一個蛋蛋
Hitler only had one ball.
好了，該行動了
JACKSON: All right, here we go.
媽的
Oh, shit.
- 我們停下幹嘛？ - 我不能撒手走人
- What are we doing?  - I can't just leave.
- 為什麼？  - 她生命有危險啊
- Why?  - She's in danger, man.
- 我們得想辦法救她   - 她死了
- We have to do something about it.  - She's dead.
- 你說她死了就死了?  - 現實點好嗎
- What do you mean, she's dead?  - Come on!
- 她才沒死呢  - 睜大你的雙眼，夥計
- She's not dead.  - Open your eyes, man.
你怎麼知道
You don't know that.
- 她死翹翹了  - 你怎麼知道她...
- She's fucking dead!  - You don't know she's...
- 你們在這裡做什麼?  - 天啊，你們找到她了
- What are you doing here?  - Holy shit, you got her.
你應該去潔西嘉家的啊
You're supposed to be at Jessica's.
是的，對不起了，馬奇先生
JESSICA: Yeah, sorry, Mr March.
我姐姐把我們趕出來了
My sister kicked us out.
- 她有朋友要來  - 她真是個騷貨
- She's having a guy over.  - Your sister's such a slut.
我知道
JESSICA: Yeah, I know.
嘿
Hello?
艾蜜莉雅
Amelia.
或許抓住她的肩膀搖一搖？
Should you shake her shoulder? Maybe...
我哥過去常用的一招，彈我的耳朵
You know, my brother used to flick my ear.
就像這樣，我討厭死了
Like that. I hated that.
- 我們不應該動粗   - 你有個哥哥？
- We shouldn't be violent.  - You got a brother?
- 你可以打她一下  - 是的
- You could just hit her.  - Yeah.
- 真的？  - 用力打
- Really?  - Like really hard.
- 我有家人的啊  - 那不太現實
- I've got a family.  - HOLLY: It's not practical.
我們想讓她開口的話，最好還是別打她
JACKSON: We probably shouldn't hit her if we want her to talk to us.
沒事了
It's okay.
你不是要替我收拾那些傢伙的嗎
You were supposed to get those guys off of me.
你知道他們是誰？誰派他們來的？
Do you know who they were? Do you know who sent them?
知道，是我媽
Yeah. It was my mother.
你介不介意給我們從頭講起
Would you mind starting from the top because...
- 為什麼，根本沒必要  - 不好意思，沒必要？
- Why? It doesn't matter.  - I'm sorry, it doesn't matter?
你朝我們開槍啊，我看很有必要
You just shot at us. I think it matters.
好吧，好吧，我拍了部電影
Okay, okay. I made a film.
跟我男朋友迪恩合作的
I made a film with Dean, my boyfriend.
最初的想法是，我們想
And the idea was that we were gonna, you know,
拍部實驗性電影
like make this experimental film,
參考藝術電影的拍法
like an artistic film.
- - 色情電影？  - 不是色情電影
- Porno film.  - It's not a porno.
你們知不知道我母親是誰？
Look, do you even know who my mother is?
恩，我們知道
Yes, we do.
實際上我們已經見過面了
We... We've actually met your mother.
她是怎麼說我的？我發神經？
What did she tell you, that I'm crazy?
跟她鬧翻了？
That I was just lashing out?
差不多吧，她可能提及了一些
Something like that. She might have mentioned...
可我母親根本就是個罪犯
Yeah, well, my mother is a criminal.
她和他們是一夥的
She's one of them.
- 他們是誰？是什麼組織？  - 那種營私舞弊的
- Who's them? What's them?  - AMELIA: One of the insiders.
那種大資本家剝削者
One of the capitalist, corporate suppressors.
他們根本就不管我們的死活
You know, they want us dead, man.
我們隨時都可以被他們丟棄
We're just in their crosshairs, you know.
就像棋子一樣
We're just pawns.
天哪
Gosh.
嗷
Ow.
嘿
Hey.
那這一切和鳥兒有什麼關係？
And what does this have to do with the birds?
對啊
JACKSON: Yeah.
我媽本該為司法部工作，對吧？
My mom's supposed to be working for the Justice Department, right?
是啊，她正在辦理尾氣淨化器的訴訟案
Sure, she's prosecuting the catalytic converter case.
沒錯，不過你被騙了，她才不會提起訴訟呢
Yeah, only she's not. She's not prosecuting it.
那些汽車廠商，她會放他們一馬
The auto makers, she's gonna let 'em walk.
- 可他們掌握了證據？  - 是啊，他們有證據的
- But they have the evidence.  - Yes, they have evidence.
他們拿到了備忘錄，裡面有底特律汽車廠商串通掩蓋尾氣淨化器作假的事
They have memos proving that Detroit conspired to suppress the converter,
證明他們寧可
proving they would rather
污染我們的空氣，也不願多花點錢去嘗試改進
poison our air than spend a little bit of money.
可我媽，她會說證據不足
But my mom, she's gonna say that's not enough.
好瞞騙過去，因為她收了錢
She's gonna lie because... Because she's on the take.
錢能收買一切，對吧？錢就是她的上帝
Money again, right? Mammon, that's her god.
這些法西斯同黨
That fascist crony...
- 好了，好了   - 自私自利的傢伙
- Okay, okay.  - ...bogart!
好了，好了，稍微冷靜點好嗎？
All right, all right, just... Just back up a little bit.
為什麼不直接找員警呢?
Why not just go straight to the police?
她就是員警
She is the police.
她就是司法部的頭頭，好嗎？
She's the head of the Justice Department.
- 你這麼說也沒錯  - 找報紙爆料？
- You... You've got a point.  - Okay, or the newspaper?
他們都是一夥的
They all work together.
天啊，你剛從山洞裡鑽出來嗎？
God, have you been living under a rock?
那好吧，可你的最佳方案是
All right, so then your solution
拍部色情電影？
was you make a porn film.
那不是色情電影
It's not a porno!
我有鄰居的
HOLLAND: You know, I have neighbours.
- 我製作了一段聲明   - 好
- I made a statement.  - JACKSON: Right.
你們說的沒錯，我的聲明裡包含有裸露鏡頭
And yeah, yeah, my statement contained nudity.
- 那種色情片的裸露鏡頭  - 是藝術電影
- Porno nudity.  - AMELIA: Art.
那只是商業推廣需要，好嗎？
That's just the commercial element, okay?
錫德說我們必須那樣做
Okay? Sid said we had to have that.
我們實際的目的是想把資訊傳達出去
And the reality was we were getting our message out there.
都包含在影片裡了
And... And it was all in the film,
姓名，日期，一切內容
names and dates and everything,
我媽參與的一切勾當
everything that my mom was doing,
一旦影片傳播出去，在影院上映
and once it was out there, once it was in theatres,
他們就不可能阻止得了了
there's no way that they could suppress it.
掩蓋也就是不可能的事了
There's no way that they could cover it up.
那容我總結一下
HOLLAND: So let me get this straight.
你拍了部劇情才是看點的色情片？
You made a porno film where the point was the plot?
你到底想表達什麼啊？
What's your hang-up, man?
重點不是性愛鏡頭
JACKSON: It's not the sex.
是故事要傳遞的資訊
It's... It's what's in the story.
我媽發現後
My mom found out.
就殺了迪恩，銷毀了影片
She killed Dean and destroyed the film.
- 迪恩是你媽殺的？  - 當然
- Your mom killed Dean?  - Of course.
- 米絲蒂也是她殺的  - 錫德·沙特克呢？
- She killed Misty, too.  - And Sid Shattuck?
她殺的
Yeah.
好吧，感覺像是開膛手傑克的故事
Okay, so it's like Jack the Ripper
不過主角換成你媽了
and then your mom, basically.
- 那你接下來有什麼打算？  - 我不知道
- So what are you gonna do?  - AMELIA: I don't know.
反正心力憔悴得很
I'm just really tired, you know.
那就這樣吧
Uh, all right, okay. So, uh, you...
我們再討論討論，你休息一會兒吧
We're just gonna talk about it and we'll think and you get some rest.
恩，你先休息下
Yeah, just get some rest.
你們怎麼看的？
What do you think?
- 我喜歡她  - 我喜歡她的裙子
- I like her.  - I like her dress.
裙子是挺好看的
It's a nice dress.
不過人就有點瘋
But she's a loon.
照她那麼說，她母親簡直就可以
According to her, her mother's single-handedly
一手遮天啊
gonna wipe out all of Western society.
是啊
Well, yeah.
可是，的確有人想要殺她，對吧？
However, there are people trying to kill her, right?
- 像約翰·博伊  - 約翰·博伊是誰？
- Like John Boy.  - Who's John Boy?
他是《沃爾頓一家》裡的  - 不是，是另一個約翰·博伊
- He's on The Waltons.  - No, different John Boy.
- 我們是這麼認為的  - 沒錯，可以肯定
- Well, we think.  - Think, yeah. Pretty sure.
到時候就知道了
Can't be sure, though. Yeah.
馬奇先生，裘蒂斯剛給我打了個電話
Mr March, I just got a call from Judith.
她也不給理由
She didn't explain herself.
就讓我去取10萬塊現金給她
Said she needed $100,000 in cash.
- 10萬塊？為什麼?  - 我也不清楚
- $100,000? Why?  -  I don't know.
我覺得她可能捲入了
I think she's involved
什麼不法交易
in something shady maybe.
她女兒肯定會表示贊同的
Well, her daughter certainly seems to think so.
艾蜜莉雅？你找到艾蜜莉雅了？
What, Amelia? You found Amelia?
是的
Yes.
她掉到我們的車上
She fell on our car.
我們正說話呢，她突然掉我們車上
We were just talking and she fell on our car.
她就在我這，你應該過來一趟
Anyway, she's here. You should come over.
我讓家庭醫生馬上過去
I... I'll send the family doctor.
呃
Okay, look,
-  馬奇先生   - 請叫我霍蘭德
-  Mr March...  - Holland, please.
送錢這事讓我有些害怕
I've got a bad feeling about this.
你能幫我把錢送過去嗎？
Would you be willing to carry the money for me?
我要是知道相信誰就好了
I wish I knew who to believe on this one.
那孩子嚇壞了，我只能這麼說了
Well, the kid's a write-off, I'll tell you that much.
也許雙方說的都是真話
Maybe they're both telling the truth.
我們在樓下
We're downstairs.
她馬上就下來
She's coming down.
雙方說的都是真話？你這是什麼意思？
What do you mean, they're both telling the truth?
那怎麼說的通？
What the fuck does that mean?
我有個朋友
I got a friend, right?
特勤處的，尼克森的手下
Secret Service. Worked the Nixon detail.
這是他下臺後的事
This was after they threw him out of office.
不了，呃
No. Anyway, you know,
尼克森一天開車出去，在聖克萊門特周邊兜風
Nixon's driving around one day around San Clemente.
- 就他和幾個特工  - 嗯
- Just him and a few agents.  - Yeah.
他們剛好遇見一場車禍
And they come across this car accident, right?
有個人被壓在車下
There's a guy pinned under a car.
於是尼克森下了車，跑過去查看那人的情況
Anyway, Nixon gets out, runs over to check on the guy,
他蹲下，對那人說道
you know, leans down, and Nixon says to him,
你不會有事的，小兄弟，你會活下來的
"You're gonna be okay, son. You're gonna be all right."
話剛說完，那人就咽氣了
And right then the guy dies.
我沒聽明白
I don't get it.
你站在當事人的角度來想想，好嗎？
Think about it from that guy's point of view, okay?
死了的那個人
The guy who died.
他正躺在地上
He's lying there on the ground,
瞪著天空，就要不行了
staring up at the sky, near death,
然後前總統理查·尼克森突然出現在他面前
and then former president Richard Nixon appears before him
還安慰他
and tells him he's gonna be fine.
他會以為這很正常嗎？對不對？
Now, did he think that's normal, right,
有多少人死前能見到尼克森的？
that before they die, everybody sees Nixon?
你期盼著天使，尼克森卻出現了
You're expecting an angel and you get Nixon.
- 就是這個意思，對吧    - 恩
- Exactly. Right?  - Yeah.
都是同樣的情形，只是以完全不同的視角來看
It's the same situation, just a vastly different point of view.
所以每件事都可以從2個方面來解讀？
So there's two ways to look at something.
對
Yeah.
這就是故事的主旨？
That's the point of the story?
- 沒錯  - 那你直說不就完了
- Yeah.  - Yeah, just say that.
什麼？
What?
我正津津有味的聽著你講的故事
Well, you just lead me on this epic fucking journey with this story,
可十分鐘後，突然撂下個“每件事都可以從2個方面來解讀”
and 10 minutes later, the point is that there's two ways to look at something.
你直說不就完了
Just... You could just say that.
你不喜歡我講的故事？
You didn't like that story?
- 那我豈不是很沒人情味  - 就是啊
- That would be awful.  - Wouldn't it, right?
- 嗯  - 很不爽，對吧？
- Yeah.  - It would suck, right?
- 噢  - 嘿
- Oh.  - HOLLAND: Hey.
謝天謝地
Thank God.
10萬塊，我親自裝好的
$100,000. Packed it myself.
真的
Just...
能有你們倆個好心人幫忙，真是萬幸啊
It's not common you find such nice people in the world.
抱歉，我沒叫他來的
I'm sorry about him.
他只是想主動幫忙而已，我也不明白
He just wanted to come along. I don't know why.
稍後我會給你電話的，我們送完貨後
But I'll call you, you know, when we make the drop.
謝謝了
Thank you.
你有沒有一絲緊張？
HOLLAND: Are you nervous at all?
我嗎？不會，我有保險的
Me? No. I got insurance.
- 藏在這的寶貝  - 腳踝槍？
- This baby right here.  - Is that an ankle gun?
- 藏在腳踝上的備用槍，沒錯  - 真是個好東西
- That is an ankle gun, yeah.  - That's pretty sweet.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我握著方向盤就要睡著了
I'm falling asleep at the wheel here, man.
得換你來開了
I'm gonna need you to drive.
我就在前面停車吧
I'm gonna pull over up here.
你不需要停下，車子可以自己開的
You don't have to pull over. The car can drive itself.
什麼?
What?
你鬆開方向盤就知道了
Just take your hands off the wheel, man.
我還不知道它們有這功能
I didn't know it could do that.
你不看新聞的嗎？
Where you been, man?
每輛車都有這個功能
Every car can do this.
就是，馬奇，你都不看新聞的嗎？
Yeah, March, where the fuck have you been, man?
白癡，連這都不知道？
Idiot. You didn't know that?
你都靠飛的，根本就不開車嘛
You fly everywhere. You don't even drive.
你懂個屁啊
What do you know?
他說的有道理，蜜蜂兄弟
He's got a point there, Bumble.
好吧，無所謂了
Yeah, whatever.
我過去都靠飛的
I used to fly all the time,
可現在這煙霧噁心死了
but now the smog is just disgusting, man.
污染指數嚴重超標
It's just this pollution is out of control.
所以現在蜜蜂都坐車出行了
All the bees are riding around in cars these days.
醒醒，快醒醒
Wake up! Wake up!
馬奇，醒醒
March! Wake up!
快醒過來
那不是鈔票
That's not money.
塔利親自裝的箱，她說的啊
Tally packed it herself. She said so.
為什麼？她為什麼要讓我們白跑一趟？
Why? Why would she send us off on some wild fucking goose chase?
艾蜜莉雅
Amelia.
- 不，像《沃爾頓一家》 - 是嗎？
- No, like The Waltons.  - Yeah?
恩，電視劇
Yeah, on TV.
理查什麼的？對
Richard something? Yeah.
- 那演員叫什麼？  - 潔西嘉，別打電話了
- Who's that actor?  - Jessica, get off the phone.
那麼，這個新出演的約翰·博伊
Yeah. Anyway, so this new John Boy's
是殺人犯之類的嗎？
like a murderer or something.
嗯
Uh-huh.
靠，我現在要想瘋了
Shit. Now it's gonna bug me.
你一定是霍利吧
You must be Holly.
我是馬利克醫生
Dr Malek.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
- 她就在屋裡，請進吧  - 謝謝
- She's inside. Come in.  - Thank you.
- 能請你爸出來嗎？  - 他出去辦事了
- You mind fetching your dad?  - Uh, he's running an errand.
- 很快就回來？  - 不，起碼要幾小時
- Back anytime soon?  - Oh, hour, tops.
好的
Fine.
那麼，小護士霍利，我們的病人還好嗎？
Now, then, Nurse Holly, how's our patient?
- 是她嗎？  - 不，那是潔西嘉
- That's her?  - Oh, no, that's Jessica.
她患的病，你可治不好
What she's got you can't fix.
你真幽默啊
You are very funny.
在那裡
In there.
睡覺呢，有點發燒
Asleep. Slight fever.
嗯
Hmm.
是不是磕了藥？，也許抽了點大麻？
On drugs you think? Maybe smoking the reefer?
她說了什麼？
What was she saying?
- 她聽上去正常嗎？  - 等等
- Was she making sense?  - JESSICA: Hold on. Um...
霍利，《沃爾頓一家》裡面演約翰·博伊的演員，他叫什麼名字？
Holly, what's the name of the guy on The Waltons that plays John Boy?
他臉上有個冰球狀的痣
With the hockey puck on his face?
那節目白癡才看
That show's for retards.
馬利克醫生，你想來塊糕點嗎，新鮮出爐的
Dr Malek, would you like a cookie? Just baked them.
都吃完了，我才看過，你忘了?
There's none left. I looked, remember?
沒有，還剩幾塊，醫生？
No, there's a couple. Doctor?
我沒那麼固執的
I could be persuaded.
等我檢查完睡美人再說吧
After I have a look at Sleeping Beauty.
小護士霍利
Nurse Holly.
霍利，你要幹什麼？你瘋了嗎？
Holly, what are you doing? Are you crazy?
吧台後面有手銬，混蛋
There are handcuffs behind the bar, asshole.
去拿過來
Get them.
這真的打亂了我的計畫，霍利
This is really slowing me down, Holly.
到底什麼情況？
What's going on?
潔西嘉，就是他，他就是那個人
Jessica, it's him. He's the guy.
潔西嘉，你要是幫我這個忙
Jessica, if you help me with this,
我就放你一條生路
I'll only kill Holly.
潔西嘉，快報警
Jessica, dial 911.
潔西嘉，我建議你最好別那樣做
Jessica, I wouldn't do that if I were you.
你聽到了嗎？
You hear that?
- 打擾了  - 晚上好
- Excuse me.  - Evening.
你聽到幾秒鐘前的響聲沒？
HOLLAND: You hear that sound just a second ago?
聽到的，就是剛才
Oh, yeah, just now.
其實是我
That was me.
把那個小姑娘丟出窗子的聲音
I threw that little girl out the window.
掩護我
Cover me.
天啊
God.
- 霍利  - 爸爸
- Holly!  - Dad!
- 進去  - 她沒事吧？
- HOLLAND: Get in.  - HOLLY: Is she okay?
低下頭
HOLLAND: Get down.
法西斯狗雜種
Fucking fascists!
天啊
Jesus!
- 對不起  - 進去
- Sorry.  - Get in.
好，過來，就待在這別亂跑
Okay, come here. Stay in here and don't move.
- 好嗎？  - 好的
- Okay.  - Okay. Okay.
等等，爸爸，這個
Wait, wait. Dad, Dad, here you go.
天啊
Jesus!
潔西嘉，她好像醒過來了
Jessica. I think she's awake.
等等，你要去哪？你這是幹嘛呢？
Wait, where are you going? What are you doing?
幫我感謝希利，儘管他沒幫到我什麼
Tell Mr Healy thanks for nothing.
操
Fuck!
你沒事吧？
Are you okay?
馬奇，槍，槍給我
March, gun, gun!
- 操  - 媽的
- Fuck!  - Shit!
給你
Here.
他跑了
He's gone.
嘿
Hey.
糟了
Shit.
哇
Wow.
幫幫忙，我得離開這
Please, I need to get out of here.
她可害死了自己的女兒，佩里
She had her fucking daughter killed, Perry.
告訴我，他們至少會訊問下她吧？
Please tell me they're at least gonna question her.
他們沒有，而且將來也不會
They haven't and they're not going to.
為什麼？
Because?
因為她是司法部的頭頭
Because she's the head of the Justice Department.
順便好意提醒下
Oh, and, by the way, you're welcome.
你們出來了，交了保證金獲得保釋，逃過一劫
You're out, free on your own recognisance. You get to walk.
你真得在家裡擺個我的雕像感謝我
There should be like a statue of me in your fucking house.
抱歉了，夥計
I'm sorry, guys.
你們還是放棄這件案子吧，好嗎？
You're gonna lose this one, all right?
雙方各執一詞，也缺乏證據，是打不贏的
Your word against hers. No evidence. You lose.
建議你們好好考慮下修改證詞的可能
You better seriously think about changing your story.
媽的，他們或許說得對
HOLLAND: Oh, fuck it. Maybe they're right.
或許這些鳥兒真的要窒息了
Maybe the goddamn birds can't breathe.
艾蜜莉雅，米絲蒂，迪恩，沙特克，統統都死了
Amelia, Misty, Dean, Shattuck, all dead.
而我們也無處伸冤
The rest of us just get to choke.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
- 我要付你多少錢，夥計?  - 12塊
- How much do I owe you, buddy?  - 12 bucks, pal.
我一直討厭那棵棕櫚樹
I always hated that palm tree.
我也總覺得它要倒
Never trusted it.
- 進屋去收拾你的東西  - 好的
- Go inside and get your stuff.  - Okay.
我們找間酒店什麼的
We'll go stay in a hotel or something.
有客房服務的那種
We'll get room service.
- 馬奇先生   - 葛籣夫人
- Mr March.  - Mrs Glenn.
我要找你談談
I need to talk to you.
你出現得真是時候啊
What a wonderful surprise.
- 這是你的房子？  - 我們正重新裝修
- Is that your house?  - We're remodelling.
聽我說，現在真不是談話的好時機
Listen, this isn't a great time.
現在正是時候
It is a great time.
他本該去找我侄女的
He is supposed to be looking for my niece.
- 真的？  - 因為我看到她了
- Really?  - Because I saw her.
可是沒人相信我
But nobody believes me.
為什麼沒人相信我？
Why will nobody believe me?
我也不知道答案啊，夫人
I'm sure I don't know, ma'am.
我看見她就在家裡
I saw her in her house
就從前面的窗戶看到的，一清二楚
through the front window as clear as day,
在桌子上寫什麼
writing something at a desk.
穿的是藍色的細條紋夾克
She was wearing a blue pinstriped jacket.
我見過那夾克，沒錯
I've seen that jacket, sure, yeah.
你說見過那夾克是什麼意思？
What do you mean, you saw that jacket?
在沙特克的辦公室
In Shattuck's office.
跟一堆衣服混在一起
It was there with a bunch of other clothes.
那夾克在沙特克的辦公室裡？
That jacket was in Sid Shattuck's office?
是啊，裝在袋子裡的
Yeah. It was bagged up.
上面寫有米絲蒂的名字，以及電影的名字
It had Misty's name on it and the name of the movie.
那是電影用的戲服
It's wardrobe for the film.
- 我他媽的明白了  - 噢！
- Holy fucking shit.  - Oh!
抱歉，葛籣夫人，你得帶我們去米絲蒂的房子
Sorry. Mrs Glenn, I need you to take us to Misty's house.
然後回憶你看到的每一個細節
I need you to show us exactly what you saw.
到了，就是這，就是那扇窗戶
MRS GLENN: There. There. That's the window.
我正要從那個角落繞過去時
I was coming around that corner
就從窗戶裡看到了她
and I saw her through that window.
可是不對啊，桌子應該在這裡啊
But, no, it was here. The desk was here.
現在桌子沒了
No desk there now.
我也不清楚怎麼會這樣
MRS GLENN: Well, I don't know what to say.
- 爸爸，你在幹嘛呢？  - 等我2分鐘
- Dad, what are you doing?  - Give me a second.
世上最差勁的偵探？
World's worst detective, huh?
你的確看見你侄女了，葛籣夫人
You did see your niece, Mrs Glenn.
你看見穿著細條紋外套，站在桌邊的她，其實是在牆上
You saw her on that wall, at a desk, in a pinstriped suit.
所以她看見的是部電影而已
So what she saw was a movie?
不是一般的電影，是那部電影
Not a movie. The movie.
- 那部電影啊  - 那電影不是燒毀了嗎？
- The movie.  - But the film burned up.
要是被燒毀了，她2天后怎麼還能看到呢？
Well, how did she see it two days after it supposedly burned up?
而且服裝也完全相同
And the wardrobe matches perfectly.
那麼艾蜜莉雅複製了一份，她還有個拷貝？
So Amelia had a second print? She had a copy?
換你也會這麼做吧
Wouldn't you?
然後她把拷貝交給米絲蒂保管
And she gave that copy to Misty.
米絲蒂死後，她就來拿回這份拷貝
So she comes here,
並且在牆上確認了一下
checks the film against that wall...
老太太剛好從視窗看到
Lily sees it through that window.
艾蜜莉雅拿到影片，然後離開
And Amelia splits and takes the film.
去了哪呢？
And goes where?
鬼才知道
Oh, for fuck...
我們就不能...
I mean, can't we get to the next...
去了西部酒店見那個商人
The Western Hotel to meet the businessman.
電影發行商
Distributors.
她去給電影發行商搞放映呢
She was screening it for the distributors.
她要放影片給他們看
She was showing them the film.
它就在外面，影片還在
It's out there. The film exists.
- 現在我們得找到它  - 你們快瞧這個
- Now we just have to find it.  -HOLLY: Guys, look.
“開幕之夜，9點”，署名是切特
"Opening night, 9:00 p.m." Signed, Chet.
- 該死的切特  - 抗議的那個傢伙？
- Fucking Chet.  - The protestor guy?
把那個給我
Give me that shit.
她跟切特計畫了什麼
She was planning something with Chet.
開幕之夜
Opening night?
洛杉磯汽車展
The LA auto show.
- 就是今天，對吧？  - 沒錯
- It's today, right?  - JACKSON: Yeah.
盛大的派對，很多重要人物參加，又有海量的媒體
Big party. Mucky-mucks. Loads of press.
要製造轟動故事，沒有比這更好的場合了
If you wanted to get a story out there, right?
切特那傢伙剛好是放映師
And fucking Chet's a projectionalist.
請別說了
MRS GLENN: Please stop talking.
我認真聽你們講了半天
I've been listening to everything you said.
那意思是我侄女真的死了？
Does this mean... Does this mean that my niece is dead?
那還有假
Yes!
抱歉，是真的
I mean, you know, yes.
- 她是被謀殺的，很抱歉  - 嗯
- She was murdered. I'm sorry.  -JACKSON: Mmm-hmm.
我們會盡力把兇手繩之以法的
But we're gonna bring down the people who did it.
是的，還可以給你多打幾折
Yeah, and for a deeply discounted rate, so...
歡迎參加洛杉磯
MC: Welcome to Los Angeles
1978年的太平洋沿岸汽車展
and the 1978 Pacific Coast Auto Show.
時尚的輪胎
Styled road wheels.
全新的節油系統
These all-new fuel-efficient systems.
制動馬力達到令人驚歎的210
MAN: An incredible 210-brake horsepower.
他們的電動3座小轎車
WOMAN: Their battery-powered  three-passenger runabout.
凱迪拉克帶來了新一代的埃爾多拉多
Cadillac have brought their new Eldorado.
裝有7升的V8引擎
...featuring a 7-litre V8.
你們知道放映室在哪嗎？
You guys know where the projection room is?
你看見切特了嗎，那個放映師？
You seen Chet, the projectionist?
他離開有10分鐘了吧，去喝酒了
Yeah, he just left like 10 minutes ago, went for a drink.
- 你是哪位？  - 我趕時間，謝了老弟
- And you are?  - In a hurry. Thanks, buddy.
你怎麼知道我的名字？
How'd you know my name was Buddy?
邁銳寶轎車
WOMAN: The Malibu sedan.
今年的新版看上去棒極了
This year's edition is looking spectacular.
大夥來瞧瞧吧
Come and see it, folks.
只是一堆車而已
JACKSON: It's just a bunch of cars.
汽車城的驕傲
Motor City Pride.
- 不是的  - 媽的
- That's not it.  - Shit.
不是我們要找的影片
That's not the film.
狗日的切特
Fucking Chet.
他可能放在什麼地方沒拿出來
He's probably still got it stashed somewhere.
塔利？天啊，你看上去美極了
Tally. Oh, my God, you look incredible.
你怎麼弄的頭髮？太華麗了
How do you get your hair to... It's magnificent.
聽著，我不知道具體什麼情況
Listen, I don't know what's going on here,
可好像有人搗鬼啊
but there's been some foul play.
你知不知道，你給我們的那個手提箱
Do you know that that suitcase that you gave us,
被人掉了包
somebody switched it out.
- 裡面裝的根本就不是錢  - 不是吧
- There was no money in it.  - TALLY: No shit.
把槍放地上，快點
Weapons on the floor. Now.
我猜你已經把放映師幹掉了吧
I guess you killed the projectionist, huh?
還沒，我同伴現在正找他呢
No. My associate's out looking for him now.
我們會找到他的
We'll find him.
塔利，我想問你個問題
Tally, let me ask you something.
你真殺過人？
You ever really killed anybody?
恩，在底特律我殺了3個
In Detroit, yeah. Three times.
真的？
Really?
全是從那開始的，底特律汽車展
That's where this all started. The Detroit show.
那個賤人米絲蒂宣傳拍了新電影的事
That bitch Misty shooting her mouth off about her new movie.
塔利，這不是真正的你，你不是個殺人兇手
Tally, this is not you. You're not a murderer.
她才說過殺了3個人的事
She just said she killed three people.
我知道，我指內心深處
I know, but I'm saying deep down.
嘿，殺一個也許可以找藉口
JACKSON: Hey, look, one's a mistake.
可殺了3個還有什麼說的
By the time you get to three...
別用你那一套評判標準好嗎
Don't paint her with that brush.
我猜活在自己的世界很容易吧
I guess it's easy to live in your world, right,
給每個人都訂上標籤
where everyone sits in their place.
看清你面對的是什麼
See what's in front of you.
她拿著槍，已經殺了3個人
She's got a gun and she's killed three...
- 現實點，兄弟  - 你不知道她經歷過什麼
- Come on, man.  - You don't know her upbringing.
- 你得面對現實好嗎  - 你又不知道她...
- You gotta face the situation.  - You don't know what she...
客房服務
Room service.
- 靠，別開槍  - 他有什麼毛病？
- Shit. No.  - What's wrong with him?
我也不清楚，等我問下
I... I don't know. I'm gonna ask him.
- 馬奇？  - 嗯？
- March?  - Yeah?
你到底搞什麼啊？
Uh, what the fuck are you doing?
你挪地方了？
Did you move it?
- 挪什麼？  - 那把槍啊
- Move what?  - The fucking gun.
- 什麼槍？  - 那把腳踝槍啊
- What gun?  - The fucking ankle gun.
誰跟你說我有把腳踝槍的？
Who told you I had an ankle gun?
你啊，那天我們一起在車裡的時候，就在撞車前
You did. In the car before we crashed.
你跟我炫耀腳踝槍
You were like, "Oh, check out my ankle gun."
還給我展示的
You know, you showed me your ankle gun.
天啊，你開什麼玩笑，腦子進水了?
Come on. Are you serious? Are you fucking serious?
- 我操  - 對了
- Oh, shit.  - JACKSON: Yeah.
是我做的夢吧？
Did I dream that?
沒錯，你個白癡，做的夢都搞不清楚
Yeah, you moron, you dreamt it.
不，不對
No, no, no, no.
哦，你說得對
Yeah, you're right, that was...
閉嘴，你們倆個都給我閉嘴
Just shut up. Shut up! Both of you.
客房服務
Room service.
- 你真是越搞越砸啊  - 閉嘴
- This takes the fucking cake.  - TALLY: Shh!
霍利，你可以進來了
Holly, you can come in now.
挺會動腦子啊，霍利
Very clever, Holly.
謝謝，我也是這麼認為的
Thanks. I thought so.
你往我身上澆冷咖啡幹嘛？
Why did you just throw cold coffee on me?
我在走廊裡拿的，還以為是熱的呢
I got it in the hallway. I thought it was hot.
我喜歡你這個點子
I like where your head's at, sweetheart.
很有可能成功的
That really could have worked out.
好了，你們都給我站角落去
All right, you know, everybody, in the corner.
動作快點
Come on.
靠
HOLLAND: Shit.
- 好吧，還是成功了  - 嗯
- Well, that really worked out.  - Yeah.
現在我們得找到切特這傢伙，不能讓約翰·博伊搶先了
Now we just gotta find that fucking Chet before John Boy does.
是的，剛才那傢伙說他喝酒去了
Yeah. Well, that guy said he was going for a drink.
你去樓頂的酒吧找，我去樓下的找
You take the roof bar. I'll take downstairs.
- 幹得漂亮，孩子  - 謝謝
- Well done, kiddo.  - Thanks.
- 你是放映師?  - 嗯
- You the projectionist?  - Mmm-hmm.
我們在9樓遇到了點麻煩
Look, we got a problem on nine.
有人把放映機打翻了
Someone knocked over the projector.
膠片滾的滿地都是
The film's all over the floor.
- 膠片全滾地上了，真的？  - 是的，真是一團糟
- Film's on the floor? Really?  - Yeah, it's a mess.
你能跟我過去嗎？
You follow me?
就像一首熱門歌曲的舊錄音
私奔 - 魯伯特·福爾摩斯
好了，你就等在這，我去四處打探一下
Okay, just wait here. I'm gonna take a look around.
可我想幫忙
I wanna help.
你守在這也是幫忙，好嗎？
You can help by staying put, okay?
你保證把電影拿到手？
Promise me you'll get the film?
好，我保證
Yeah, I promise.
拉個勾才算數？
Pinky promise?
如果你喜歡冰鎮果子朗姆酒
靠
Fuck.
如果你喜歡冰鎮果子朗姆酒
靠
Fuck.
正好漫步到雨中
如果你沒有迷上瑜伽
如果你還有半個腦子
嘿，夥計，你想要點什麼？
Hey, pal, what can I do you for?
如果你還有半個腦子
嘿，夥計，你想要點什麼？
Hey, pal, what can I do you for?
免費酒水，隨你點
Free drinks. What do you have?
小個子，細頭髮的
Little guy, stringy hair.
他們應該是從那扇門出去了
I think they went out through those doors.
嘿，切特，切特
Hey, Chet? Chet?
嘿，切特
Hey. Hey, Chet.
艾蜜莉雅的影片，放在哪的？
Amelia's film, where is it?
影片就在放映機裡，重複一遍，在放映機裡
The film is in the projector. Repeat, it's in the projector.
可我們檢查過了啊？
But we already checked that.
- 拼接進去的  - 什麼？
- Spliced in.  - What?
它是拼接在其他影片裡的，趕快去取
It's spliced into the middle of it, right in the other film. Go get it.
我這就去
On my way.
你不知道偷聽別人說話是很不禮貌的嗎？
Don't you know it's rude to eavesdrop?
我有把槍就抵在你女兒背後
I got a gun pointed directly at your daughter's spine.
跟我走一趟吧，走吧，寶貝
Come with me. Come on, baby.
這歌怎麼樣？
How does that song go?
歡迎光臨，洛杉磯市民
NARRATOR: Welcome, Los Angeles,
讓我們欣賞底特律推出的一批上等車型
to the finest fleet of automobiles Detroit has to offer,
向世界展示奢華的全新定義
giving the world luxury redefined.
除了獨樹一幟的設計風格
In addition to the most distinctive styling,
我們的內飾也會確保你有舒適的駕車體驗
we are bringing you interiors that are comfort assured,
混合使用絲絨、皮革
combining velour, leather,
以及木制儀錶盤
wood panelling and an improved...
幫下你爸爸
Help him up.
你為什麼要把倒楣孩子也帶來
Why'd you have to bring the goddamn kid?
- 我搞砸了  - 對，你搞砸了
- I fucked up.  - Yeah, you fucked up.
美國
NARRATOR: America...
米絲蒂·芒滕絲出演
《你喜歡我的車嗎？大男孩》
天啊
Oh, my God.
靠，靠
Fuck, fuck.
你希望你孩子看到你這副模樣？
Do you want her to see you like this?
你個醉鬼
You fucking drunk.
別他媽的擠貓尿了
Oh, don't start that crying shit.
- 我搞砸了  - 你這個爛酒的垃圾
- I fucked up.  - You drunk motherfucker, you.
- 我愛你  - 真是丟人現眼
- I love you.  - It's embarrassing.
我很抱歉，蹲下
I'm sorry. Duck.
- 什麼？  - 蹲下
- What?  - Duck.
你媽的
Motherfucker!
我是暴脹保爾森
Well, I'm Bulging Paulsen
我代表的是底特律的汽車廠商
and I represent the Detroit auto manufacturers.
我就是這麼厲害
That's who the hell I am.
你污染我們的空氣，大家是不會容忍的
You poison our air. The people won't stand for it.
尼克森
Nixon!
不能死
No!
我可以被說服，改變心意的
MISTY: I might be persuaded to change my mind.
或許我們就價錢達成一致的話
Perhaps if we came to a monetary arrangement.
我用電匯收賬，帳號是聯邦行會的
I'll take a wire transfer. It's a Union Federal account.
號碼是22-12
Number 22-12.
告訴他們準確的數字
Just tell them the exact amounts.
他有槍！
He's got a gun!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
3，2，1
Three, two, one.
天啊
Jesus!
你跑下面來幹嘛，我不是讓你去屋頂嗎？
How'd you get down here? I told you to go to the roof.
- 你又摔了一跤？  - 是的
- Did you fall?  - Yeah.
天啊，你說真的？
Jesus Christ, are you kidding?
我覺得自己堅不可摧
I think I'm invincible.
只有這一個解釋了
It's the only thing that makes sense.
- 我相信自己死不了  - 影片在哪？
- I don't think I can die.  - Where's the film?
還在上面，我們只能去取了
It's up there. We just gotta go get it.
給我出去，你個小雜碎
You get out of here, you little shit.
交給我，你這個嬉皮小瘋子
You give me that, you fucked-up little hippy.
你想要啊，自己去搶啊
You want it? Go get it.
別扔
No!
快把那個影片奪過來，快去
Get me that fucking film. Move it.
- 掩護我  - 什麼？馬奇，馬奇
- Cover me.  - What? March! March!
放下武器
GUARD: Drop your weapon!
操
Fuck.
馬奇，快走，這交給我了
March, go. I got this.
嘿
Hey!
MAN: Hey!
跑，快跑！
MAN: Run! Just run!
希利大叔，你在做什麼啊？
Mr Healy, what are you doing?
別管我，霍利
Go away, Holly.
希利，住手，你用不著殺他的
Healy, stop. You don't have to kill him.
希利大叔，你要是殺了這個人，我永遠都不會理你了
Mr Healy, if you kill this man, I will never speak to you again.
祝賀你了，老弟
Congratulations, buddy.
你的命是這個13歲的小姑娘救下的
You owe your life to a 13-year-old girl.
好了，我們下去找你爸吧
Come on, let's go down and see your dad.
下面又交給員警了
And that would be the cops.
先生？你沒事吧?
OFFICER: Sir? Sir, are you all right?
還有人困在裡面嗎？
Sir, is anyone left in the building?
他沒反應
He's not responsive.
好吧，讓我們看下還有誰...
All right, let's find out who else is...
可有時候，有的時候
HOLLAND: And sometimes, sometimes...
你就是功成生退
You just win.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
尷尬了
Oh, shit.
這麼辦，別跟她說話
You know what? Don't even talk to her.
連看都別看她
Don't even look at her, man.
操
Fuck.
小兄弟啊
Oh, boys, boys.
你們真以為伸張正義了啊？
You really think you got something done here.
你們明白發生了什麼嗎？
Do you have a clue what just happened?
這都是約定俗成，我只不過隨大流而已
It was protocol. I followed protocol.
（學德語）
他有什麼毛病？
What's wrong with him?
我相信他是拿你和阿道夫·希特勒做比較
I believe he's making a connection between you and Adolf Hitler.
多看看報紙吧
Read the fucking newspaper.
只要底特律發展了，美國也會更加繁榮
What's good for Detroit is good for America.
難以置信
Unbelievable.
我熱愛的美國是三巨頭造就的
The America I love owes its life to the Big Three.
那害死自己的女兒也是正當的？
But it's all right for you to fail your daughter?
- 是底特律害死了她  - 看報紙怎麼說吧
- Detroit had her killed.  - I think I read about that.
整座城市都行動起來了，很多人出來投票
The whole city got together, took a vote. Big turnout.
我想要救她的，所以我才會雇傭你們
I wanted her safe. That's why I hired you two.
你就要進牢房了，庫特納女士
You're going to jail, Mrs Kuttner.
你說的也許沒錯
I might be going to jail,
可那也不會改變現狀
but it won't make a difference.
你們是扳不倒底特律的
You can't take Detroit down.
就算我沒法再打理這一切
And if I'm not there to take care of it,
別人也會接手的
someone else will be.
好吧，我們走著瞧了
Okay, well, we shall see.
聖誕快樂，大家，聖誕快樂！
Merry Christmas, everybody. Merry Christmas!
天啊
Jesus.
他在哪？
Where is he?
威士卡
Scotch.
你看電視了？
Did you see the TV?
恩，看了
Yeah, I saw.
他們不會追究責任，那些汽車廠商毫髮無損
They're gonna let them off, the car companies, scot-free.
說沒有足夠證據表明有串通行為
Not enough evidence of collusion, you see.
我聽說了
I heard.
日復一日，年復一年
The sun went up, the sun went down.
一切都還是老樣子，就和她說的一樣
Nothing changes, just like you said.
他們逃過了懲罰，是很讓人失望
Look, they got away with it. Big surprise, you know?
民眾好騙，可也有覺醒的一天
People are stupid. But they're not that stupid.
關鍵是，最多五年
The point is five years tops,
我們都會開上日本產的電動車
we're all driving electric cars from Japan, anyway.
記住我的話
Mark my words.
瞧瞧這個
Look at this.
你見過口臭領帶嗎?
You ever see the bad-breath tie?
對著它吹口氣
Breathe on it.
屢試不爽，每次都能逗樂霍利
Works every time. Kills Holly.
至少你又喝酒了
At least you're drinking again.
是啊，痛快極了
Yeah. I feel great.
- 反正也沒人受傷  - 有人受傷的
- You know, nobody got hurt.  - A few people got hurt.
我的意思是，那些人都死得很痛快
I'm saying I think they died quickly, though,
所以我覺得那不算受傷
so I don't think that they got hurt.
給你看看這個
Look at this.
好夥計偵探所
給你看看這個
Look at this.
好夥計偵探所
- 抱歉把你畫的像菲律賓人   - 是有點
- I'm sorry you look Filipino.  - I do.
哦，也有點像墨西哥人
Or I look Mexican.
我們已經接到了第一宗案子
HOLLAND: And we already got our first case.
- 格倫代爾一個老太太   - 嗯？
- Old lady in Glendale.  - Mmm-hmm.
懷疑她丈夫和琳達·卡特有姦情 （女演員，出演過神力女超人）
Thinks her husband's sleeping with Lynda Carter.
和神力女超人？
Wonder Woman?
或者琳達·卡特
Or Lynda Carter.
這就需要我們去調查個清楚了
That's what we have to figure out.
好吧
Right.
不過她丈夫82歲了，所以得抓緊時間
But he's 82, so it's time-sensitive.
合作愉快？
What do you say?
媽的
Shit.
- 敬鳥兒一杯  - 感謝上帝
- To the birds.  - Hallelujah.